Sunny: Good evening to all of you, let's, begin with the class. If I'm audible, guys, then,
Sunny: Please, confirm in the chat.
Sunny: Oh.
Sunny: Okay, so let's start with the session. Give me a moment, guys, I'm going to start, okay?
Sunny: Fine, so guys, let's begin with the session. Let's start with this class. I hope I am visible and audible, so we can start.
Sunny: And let me check the recording, whether the recording is updated or not over the dashboard.
Sunny: Okay, guys, so the recording is updated, you can check out with the dashboard. I think the title is not correct, just a second, guys, let me change the title of it.
Sunny: What I explain, I explain.
Sunny: Data ingestion for the RAG and the RAG introduction.
Sunny: So I discuss only the RAG introduction.
Sunny: I think now the title is correct, RAG introduction. So we just discussed about the RAG, and today, guys, we'll more focus over the data parsing. Got it?
Sunny: So, how's your Sunday going on?
Sunny: I can see the attendance is low today.
Sunny: I think many of you, you went for the movie or something, right?
Sunny: Mall, movies, or somewhere, correct?
Sunny: My holiday's on Monday, not Sunday.
Sunny: Mmm, welcome to the jungle.
Sunny: Because the mall is beside to my apartment, I've seen the very, huge, the very long queue, actually, in front of the, the movie, basically, this one, Inox.
Sunny: So, I thought, like, some… any new movie came, maybe.
Sunny: Hmm. Okay.
Sunny: Where do you stay so I stay in the Bengaluru?
Sunny: Excuse me
Sunny: Great, guys. So, let's start with the session. Yesterday, I think I was talking about the, parsing, correct? The data parsing. I discussed about the RAG.
Sunny: And basically, we understood each and everything about the RAG. What is the RAG, and how does it work? Okay, theoretically, basically, I explain you each and everything. So this is all the notes which I already provided you.
Sunny: you can directly download these notes from my GitHub itself, and even these notes will be available in the resource section, so from there also, you can take it. Got it?
Sunny: Now, let's, do one thing, guys. Let's, go with the practical. Let's perform one… some practical.
Sunny: And, guys, this, RAG, actually, it is more about the practical. So, from, next week onwards, we'll be more focusing over the practical itself than this theory. So, I will explain the theoretical concept wherever it is required, but, yeah, we'll more focus over the practical only. Got it?
Sunny: Is it clear?
Sunny: Jap se ya ya ya hai, jandi ki tawa ho rakhi hai, ye
Sunny: Yeah, this is, right, but,
Sunny: Guys, see, the AI is not a new thing, right? So, it came, I think, around in 2019-20 itself.
Sunny: And at that time, the data science boom was there, right? Data science, machine learning, and the deep learning, correct? So from that time, actually, I'm learning all the stuff in the same way, like I'm teaching you today, okay?
Sunny: So, the AI is not a new thing, which, recently came up in 2022 or 23. Yeah, the AI boom actually came after the ChatGPT, but, guys, the data science, MLDL, again, it was, not, like, the simple one, right?
Sunny: If you're going to be start that again and again, the revision would be required around to that, okay? So once you are into this loop, AI, ML, and all, then, like, you will have to spend, more time over here.
Sunny: Okay, then your regular job, right? Whatever you are doing, your work and all, the base… the development and all, right? Along with that, actually, you will have to spend enough amount of time over this AI, over this data science and all.
Sunny: Yeah, correct.
Sunny: So, let's, do one thing, guys. First, let me open the VS Code, and, here only I will show you all the practical and all. So, give me a moment.
Sunny: I'm creating a new folder, inside the same repository.
Sunny: So, just a second.
Sunny: Okay, the code is here.
Sunny: Just give me a second, okay? Wait, guys.
Sunny: -H
Sunny: So, some unnecessary files were there, so I'm just removing that, I'm just cleaning the directory, okay? Give me a minute only.
Sunny: Let me do it.
Sunny: Okay, great, guys.
Sunny: So, just a second, I'm giving you the data and all everything, so on top of that only, we are going to perform the, data parsing, right? So, the data parsing concept is clear now. Theoretically, I think everyone is able to understand what is a data parsing.
Sunny: It'll be yes or no.
Sunny: Okay. So I created a new folder, and inside this folder, I kept a data folder as well. Now, here, basically, you will see the different, different files.
Sunny: So, I kept the TXT file, HTML file, PDF file, DOCX file, JSON file, CSV file. Okay, each and every file is there, so I'll basically explain each and everything around to this file. First, we'll see the simple data loader, how we can load the data using the LangChain.
Sunny: And then we'll see the complex parsing, right? So even I kept the complex parsing also, so we'll definitely discuss around to that as well.
Sunny: So, this folder is not required, let me delete this also.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, this is the latest folder, class 30. Now, inside this folder, guys, you can see we have so many data files, okay? Inside this data folder, we have so many data files. So, I kept some complex example also, so later on we'll look into those particular example.
Sunny: So I'm going to be open one of the PDFs. See, this is the PDF, guys. I kept this kind of P
Sunny: So, I will show you how, basically, you can parse this type of PDF, and how you can do the arrangement of the data. So, we'll do the arrangement of the data in the JSON file, into the MD file, and then further, we are going to be utilizing that file for creating a RAG, okay?
Sunny: So, whenever we are talking about the real time, correct? So, in the real time, basically, you will see a lot of complexity inside the PDF and the data, okay? When you are parsing the data. Yes or no, guys? Tell me.
Sunny: If you have ever, gone through with the data, if you have ever gone through with a PDF and all, right? So there, basically, you will find out, lots of complexity in terms of data. So first, guys, what we will discuss, we'll discuss, like, whatever, we'll discuss basically whatever,
Sunny: Like, the loader is available in the lantern itself.
Sunny: The data loader will, do the discussion around to that, and after that only, we'll come where? After that only, guys, we'll come to the complex, complex data parsec.
Sunny: So, if you will, look into this particular document, so inside this document, you will find out each and every kind of, data. So, text data is also there, now this chart is also there, okay? Now, here you can see the table.
Sunny: Now, again, you will find out some more tables, some complex table also, right? So see some complex table. Now, again, it's a flow chart. Again, it's a table.
Sunny: Now see, this is a normal table. This is the one of the OCR image, okay?
Sunny: Even I capped this also. So we'll see how basically we can, get the data from this OCR image, okay? Then guys, you will find out some other complex table, let me show you that. So see, this is one of the heat, map, right? And then, basically we have…
Sunny: Other tables, other text, okay? Then, see, this is a complex table where we have multiple cells, okay? Inside the one cell itself, we have a multiple cell.
Sunny: Okay, and the 2-cell is merged over here, right? So, sorry, 2-cell is the split one over here, right? And here you can see the 2 is the merged one, 2-cell is the mer
Sunny: Then, you can see this is, again, one of the kind… one of kind of… one of the table, right? It is, again, a complex example of the table. Then, guys, you will see this… this type of table, okay? Then, guys, you will see, again, some images, see some, charts and all.
Sunny: Then see, again, basically some flowcharts, basically I capped over here. This is the scanned image inside the PDF, okay?
Sunny: then you will find out my image also, so I kept, just for giving you the example, this is my image, right? So this kind of data, basically, we are going to be parse. Got it, guys? Yes or no? So this is a complex PDF, so here I'll show you, basically, how to parse this kind of PDF.
Sunny: Now, apart from that, just to show you the example of the different, different, data loader from the LangChain, I kept the different, the document. So, we have the MD file also over here, then we have a CSV file, okay? So, I'll show you how you can load the CSV file, the JSON file, DOCX file is also there, PDF is also there, a simple PDF, basically.
Sunny: Then HTML file, okay, text file, again, MD5. So, even I will show you that as well, right?
Sunny: So, is it, getting clear? Tell me, guys, the idea and the agenda are clear, related to this data parsing. Now, we're talking about the data parsing. Now, guys, even you can do the practice on top of the different other data set also.
Sunny: So, what you can do, even I figure out some, different data set, okay? On top of that, you can do some, practice. So, let me share those link as well with all of you. Now, see, this is, one of the link, guys, okay?
Sunny: So from here, you can download some PDF, some complex PDF, and you can perform the data parsing. And on top of that also, you can create a rag. So this is the website from the Coca-Cola, investorcocacolacompany.com. So over here, they are giving you some data set, the real time invoicing and all. Once you will click on it, you will find out some real time invoicing and all.
Sunny: So, you can download this kind of dataset just to perform some data parsing and all, and on top of it, you can create your RAG. Now, again, this is not one of the, data, link. Okay, I have the other one also, let me show you. See, I have figured out one website also.
Sunny: So, it's a government website. So, from here, also, you can download some annual report, okay, some quarterly reports, the report related to the different economic software and all. So, even from there, also, you can take some data set, and on top of that, you can perform some data parsing. Got it? Now, again, I have some more, basically.
Sunny: links, okay? I can share with all of you. So, see, this is, again, one more link, doc, VQA. So, here, basically, again, you will find out some, OCR-related data set. You can download this data set, and on top of that, you can perform the data parsing, okay? You can practice your data parsing.
Sunny: Now, different, different basically data you will get. See, again, one more link is there. Fun SD. Okay, fun SD. So you can download the data set from here. Again, it's an invoice data, OCR data, table related data. So on top of that, again, you can practice the data parsing. So this is some real time data set. From here, you can download the data.
Sunny: And then, basically, on top of that, you can practice the data parsing. Getting my point?
Sunny: Yes?
Sunny: Okay, so if the idea is clear, just let me know so that I can proceed. Someone is saying frequently the connection is disconnecting. Guys, my connection is good now. Everyone is able to hear me properly, correct?
Sunny: Okay, so my connection is good, even you can see the other chats also.
Sunny: So, I'm sharing this link with all of you, and even I will keep inside the GitHub also, okay?
Sunny: From there also, you can take it.
Sunny: So guys, I hope this is a good, like,
Sunny: resources, okay? From there, you can download some real-time data, and on top of that, you can perform some data parsing. You can practice some data parsing. Got it?
Sunny: Good.
Sunny: So, this is clear. Now, let's do one thing, guys. Let's start with the Langchain Loader. So, yesterday, basically, we have talked about the Langchain Loader. Langchain Loader is an important one, because we are going to use those Langchain Loader in our pipeline as well. So, wherever it is required, we'll use that Langchain Loader, okay, inside our pipeline.
Sunny: So first, let me show you all the practical using the LangChain loader. So what I'm doing, guys, here I'm going to create one more file.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: Data parsing, part 1.
Sunny: Langchain Loader.
Sunny: LinkedIn. Data.
Sunny: loaded.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: dot IPYNB.
Sunny: So, this is the file, guys, which I have created. Now, what I'll do, guys, here, basically, I will select my kernel. So, please select your appropriate kernel, which you are using. So, please verify first which kernel you are using over here.
Sunny: Right, while you are installing these requirements, and then select the same kernel over here as well, inside the notebook. Got it?
Sunny: So, let me select the correct kernel, so this is my correct kernel.
Sunny: Okay, now let me close this co-pilot, and let me zoom the screen so that you can clearly see the entire practical. Is it visible now? Tell me, guys, yes or no?
Sunny: So let me check whether, the code is working or not. So here, simply, I can write ALL, OK.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: So everything is working fine, everything is set now, so let's, start with the practical. So guys, just give me quick final confirmation if the agenda, the idea is clear, so that, we can start with the practical. Yes or no?
Sunny: So.
Sunny: Okay. So, first of all, let's do one thing.
Sunny: Let me write some theoretical points so that you will get some idea.
Sunny: Here is what?
Sunny: Here is some theoretical point, okay?
Sunny: So, you can see, guys, you can read out this point, what I have written.
Sunny: Just, read this out.
Sunny: Are you reading?
Sunny: So here basically I return in Langchain, we can we can call them the data loaders, right? So Langchain is providing you the different different data loaders. So they load the data files, they load the files like PDF, DOCX, CSV, TXT, HTML and the JSON. Internally they may use the parcel like the PI PDF, DOCX to DOC to TXT unstructured or JQ for the JSON.
Sunny: to extract the content. Then LangChain convert the external content into the document. So this is the standard way of collecting our data inside the LangChain, okay? So if you are going to extract the data inside the LangChain, guys, so you will get that particular data in a document form.
Sunny: Right? So the document format, basically, it's a standardized format, so every loader basically will provide you the data inside this document format, and then that further, you can utilize the document format inside the RAG pipeline. Getting my point? Yes or no?
Sunny: Okay. Now, over here, guys, I am going to write, a couple of more lines, so just, read this line also carefully.
Sunny: So, in LangChain, parsed content comes in the document object, okay? So, document the parsed content, whatever content you are going to be parsed using the LangChain loader, so it will come in the document object.
Sunny: Now, inside the document object, basically, you will get the page content, and you will get the metadata, right? So this format is useful for the RAG, because later we can show the source citation along with the final answer.
Sunny: So, just forget this particular line, I'm removing it, just read till over here. So, if we are going to be extract any data set, any… if we are going to be extract the data from any file, okay, inside the LangChain.
Sunny: Then, guys, the data, basically, it will come in the form of document object. Got it? I will show you practically, so that you will get some idea over here. So let me, do one thing, let me write some code.
Sunny: So first, guys, I'm going to be import something, okay? Couple of modules. So I have a text loader, PDF loader, then CSV loader, then I have doc to TXT loader, okay?
Sunny: then unstructured HTML loader, and then the JSON loader. So, I have these many loaders. These are the classes from the LangChain. I'm going to be using these particular classes.
Sunny: For loading the data from the document. Got it?
Sunny: Is it clear, guys? Tell me.
Sunny: Yeah, anywhere you can use that, LangChain RCs, right? So, can we force to use only a specific library for data parsing? Specific li- automatically, it will use Namon.
Sunny: So once we'll utilize this class, now automatically that library will be used in the backend. We don't need to mention that explicitly. Got it? Mohan?
Sunny: Okay. So here, guys, what I'm doing, I'm just going to be import the different or different classes. Got it?
Sunny: So, now what I'm… yeah, basically PyMU PDF, PDF Plumber also, you can use it directly, that is not at all… that is not at all an issue. But guys, just to make the entire pipeline a standardized one, I'm using the same, data loader.
Sunny: Which was, defined inside the LangChain. Because, going forward also, the chunking, embedding, data model loading, vector database, I'm going to use the LangChain only. So everything would be in a, everything would be basically over the LangChain itself.
Sunny: and whatever data we are loading, it will be loaded in the document object format, so further we can utilize it in our pipeline. Got it? So you will understand this entire thing once I will show you the entire practical, the entire RAG pipeline. So just wait for two to three more classes, this entire idea will be clear, okay?
Sunny: First, let me discuss something around the data parsing, because, this is important one. Now, let me do one thing, let me import it. So, guys, you can see the, classes are importing.
Sunny: No, you cannot specify that.
Sunny: So, over here, guys, so first, what I'm doing, I'm going to show you the PDF loader. So, let's see, basically, how we can load the PDF data. So, for that, I no need to do anything, I just need to take this particular class, the PDF loader class. Now, here, what I'll do, guys, so you can see, we have so many, basically, parameter over here.
Sunny: So, I'm just going to be mention the file path right now, okay? And then we'll load the data. So, here, guys, inside the data folder, I kept the different, different files and folder. So, sorry, I kept the different, different files, basically, with the different, different extension. So, I'm just taking, I'm just taking that file. So, where is the PDF file?
Sunny: So, here is one sample PDF I have created. Sample PDF document. Sample document.pdf. Okay, so I'll copy the path of it, and I'll paste it over here, right? So, let me paste this path over here, and then once I'll run it, guys, I will be able to load this PDF.
Sunny: So let me load this PDF. What I'm doing, I'm just going to…
Sunny: create an object of it. So, this is going to be my loader. Okay, once I will execute it, see, my data will be loaded. Okay? How I can check the data? So, if I will check with this loader.
Sunny: So I will just get an object. This is my object.
Sunny: Now, on top of the object, guys, I will call some function. So, this object, actually, it is providing me the different, different function.
Sunny: like add, append, capitalize, cache fold, so many attributes and different, different functions you will get, okay? Which is defined inside this particular class. So, it provides us one function that… the function name is what? Load function. So, I will simply call that load function, L-O-A-D.
Sunny: Okay, so once I'll call this load function, I will be able to load the data. So let me show you the data now, see? The data is coming. So, inside the data, basically, you will find out two main keys.
Sunny: Okay, so let me… Show you that key.
Sunny: So I will, keep it inside the, where I will keep it, guys, I will keep it inside this variable. Now, see, this variable is having the data.
Sunny: I can show you the data. See, this variable is having a data. Now, let me show you the document object, in which the data have been converted. Now, see, this is my document object. Now, inside the document object, how many keys we have? Can anyone tell me? If we're talking about this document object, how many keys we have over here?
Sunny: I think I just told you, we have two keys. So the first key is what? The first key is the metadata, and the second key is the page content.
Sunny: Okay, so metadata basically it is keeping the basically it is keeping some information about the PDF, right? What is a PDF path from where the PDF is coming? What is the title? Okay, when this data object have been created and the page content, the exact content of the PDF will be available.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: So this is the exact content of the PDF. So let me, show you how to extract this, PDF content. So once I will call this docs0.
Sunny: Metadata.
Sunny: Okay, so I will get the metadata from here. Now, see, this is the metadata.
Sunny: Okay? Metadata means the information about the data.
Sunny: And now, if I will call the page content on top of it, so here, guys, you will get what?
Sunny: You will get the actual data. So, see, this is the actual data of the PDF.
Sunny: Is it getting clear? So let me write the print over here.
Sunny: Okay, so let me write the print statement. Let me write this thing inside the print statement, so you will find out the exact data. So this data is being parsed, this data is being parsed from where? From the PDF itself. So if you will look into the PDF, guys, so see, this is the PDF.
Sunny: Let me show you the PDF side by side. I can open the PDF. Just a second.
Sunny: So this is the PDF.
Sunny: Okay? This is the PDF, guys.
Sunny: So I'm able to parse this particular PDF. Now, over here, you will see we have the table, okay? But the table data is also extracted. It is not visible in the form of the table, okay? It is a raw data itself.
Sunny: Now, how to arrange the data in the form of table, okay? How to extract it, in the form of table, okay? So I will show you going forward. So we can arrange the data in the AMD file, or else we can keep the data into the JSON file. But as of now, the entire raw data is coming.
Sunny: Making sense? Is it clear?
Sunny: So, this is what, guys, this is called the PDF loading, okay, or the PDF parsing, because in the backend, it is using the PyMuPDF library.
Sunny: What it is doing, guys, it is using the PyMuPDF library, so it is able to parse the data. Now, we'll do some, in-depth level of parsing. See?
Sunny: this is a partial data parsing, okay? Actually, the definition of the data parsing is what? The definition of the data parsing is to, fetch the, important component, to arrange the data according to our requirement. That is the actual definition of the data parsing.
Sunny: Now, simply, we can say over here, it's a data loading, or data extraction. Data extraction, or partial data parsing, it's a correct word for this one. Got it? So, I hope this entire thing is clear, this data parsing example is clear. Got it, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: If this part is getting clear, I will show you more example. Don't worry, everything will come, Aditi, okay? We'll understand that. Images and all, I'll show you that.
Sunny: So, if this part is getting clear, I hope it is, Like,
Sunny: It's very easy to understand, nothing is here. Let me close it, close this PDF, and let me show you the further example. So guys, we are able to load the PDF, but what, what all different type of data loader are available inside the LangChain, okay?
Sunny: What are the different type of loader is available inside the link chain? So let me do one thing.
Sunny: Let me add those, loader also.
Sunny: So, what I'm doing, guys, I'm showing you the text loader. Okay, so even we can load the text file as well. So, here what I'm doing, I'm going to create an object of the text loader class, and there also I will be passing the path of the text file. So, here, basically, let me pass the path of the text file.
Sunny: So, see? This is the path of the text file. Okay?
Sunny: So this is what is the path of the text file, this one.
Sunny: Now, what I'll do, guys, I will create an object.
Sunny: So, let me create an object over here, TXT underscore loader.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Now, guys, see, the object is created. Now, on top of this object, I will create a function. I will call the method. The method name is going to be load, so simply I'll call what? I'll call the load function.
Sunny: Okay? So once I will call the load function, the data is going to be loaded. So it's saying, what is the issue over here? Let me check it out.
Sunny: Parallel loading into this file… do we not have this file? SampleTXT.txt. Just a second, guys, let me keep the correct file path.
Sunny: I think it is not a correct name. So let me do one thing. Let me write the text text. Okay, let me run it. And again, I'm going to call this load method. Now see, I will be able to load the data. So this is what guys, this is my text one text file. So txt underscore docs. Got it guys.
Sunny: So, this is my txt dataset. So, let me write over here, txt doc. Now, I can show you, see, what you will get, guys. Again, you will get the data in the standardized format, that is a document object. Now, from, this particular object, you can, check out the metadata.
Sunny: So, let me, show you the metadata over here. Just a second, let me show you the metadata.
Sunny: And then I'll show you the page content. Okay, so here, basically, what we have, we have,
Sunny: the first object, and then here, basically, is what I'm just going to be called the metadata. So, see, this is the metadata, basically, which we are able to get. You can simply print this, you will get that metadata, okay?
Sunny: See, this is the metadata. Now, what I can show you guys, I can show you the page content as well. So, simply, I can call what? I can call the…
Sunny: page content, okay? So, see, this is the page content which I'm able to get. Now, I can show you the text document, so just a second.
Sunny: Let me open the text document. See, this is a simple text file, so we are able to load this particular text file using what? Using the LangChain itself, okay? So I'm not going to rewrite the text, I'm not… I haven't written the text loader, okay, separately.
Sunny: I can do that, I can simply load the text file, okay? We have the file operation in the Python. Using that file operation, we can load that, but yeah, everything is being written in the backend, in the LangChain only, so I'm directly using the LangChain classes. Is it making sense?
Sunny: Is it making sense to all of you? Tell me, guys, it is very easy to understand.
Sunny: And, I hope, everyone is able to understand. So I'm, just showing you that what all type of different, different loaders we have.
Sunny: And then, whenever we are going to be build a RAG, I will take a bigger document, okay? The document, basically with, around, 10 to 15 pages at least, okay? Or more than that. Even I can take a document with around 50 pages. Got it?
Sunny: So here, basically, I'm just showing you that, what is our different, different document loaders we have.
Sunny: Now, I hope this part is clear. Now, do one thing, guys. Let's, understand.
Sunny: What all the… what is the meaning, actually? What is the meaning of this, particular metadata, okay? Let me explain you that. So, it is very easy to understand. Easily, you can, understand this part. Just a second.
Sunny: Let me remove it from here, let me keep it in the next code one.
Sunny: So see what is there inside the metadata. Inside the metadata, basically, you will find out the source. In the txt, basically, you will just find out the source from where the data is coming, right? Now, if you are checking with the PDF one, so here you will find out the more detail. In the metadata, you will find out the producer name, okay, creator.
Sunny: Creator of this, basically document, okay? It is unspecified. Creation date when this document object have been created. Author name is anonymous, right? Then, keyword is non-modified date, right?
Sunny: So, again, the same date is there, the subject, title, we haven't specified anything over here related to this PDF, okay?
Sunny: Then trapped falls, then source basically from where the data is coming. Total pages, how many pages we have, okay? So it is starting the indexing from the page. It is starting the indexing from the zero. That's why the page zero over here, right? Page label is one. So we just have one pages, and the indexing is starting from the zero, okay? That's why it is saying page zero over here.
Sunny: Got it? So these all are the things coming inside the metadata. If you wanted to utilize any sort of information, you can utilize that. And going forward, I will show you basically how you can create your own custom document object. Okay? So we'll understand how you can create your own custom document object. Making sense? Yes or no?
Sunny: Is it getting clear to all of you? If it is getting clear, then I think we can, move forward.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Tell me, guys, is this part clear? Just give me a quick thumbs up so that I can… Proceed.
Sunny: Yes?
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Yeah, correct, index 0. This page label is nothing, means, basically it is representing the first, it is representing to the first page.
Sunny: It is representing what? It is representing to the first page, okay?
Sunny: If we're talking about the trap, so trap is nothing, what is the meaning of trap? See, whenever we are, talking about the PDF, na, so for the PDF printing, okay, we had some color, combination, right? So…
Sunny: To basically, what I can say, guys, to indicating that color and all, na, inside the PDF,
Sunny: Okay, so we use this particular, this particular key, trapped key.
Sunny: I am not basically sure about it. You can check out, but yeah, when I have checked all the metadata keys and all, it was the same definition. You can explore more about it. What is this trapped? Okay, why they are mentioning it? Just check out that. Got it?
Sunny: Okay. I think it is all about the color, basically. What the color formatting is being applied inside the PDF. It is all about that, this one.
Sunny: Now, I hope this is clear, so let's do one thing, guys. Let's understand the other different, different loader, okay? So what I can do, guys, I can show you the other kind of loader. See, even this is providing the CSV loader also, this LangChain. So let me,
Sunny: basically create an object of the CSV loader. See, guys, here's the class, the CSV loader, okay? I'm going to create an object of that.
Sunny: Now, what I will do, guys, I will mention the path of that file. So, I'm just going to copy the path, and then I'm passing it over here.
Sunny: Got it? Now, what I'll do, guys, after that, I'll create an object of it. I'll keep it inside the…
Sunny: I will keep this object inside the variable. So, CSV loader. Okay, this is the object.
Sunny: Now, after that, guys, what I'll do, I'll create an object of this class, and then I will call what? I will call the load method.
Sunny: So, for every class, guys.
Sunny: for every class, you need to be called the same method. And for this standardization only, we are using this LangChain wrapper. Okay? So I'm, calling this load method. Now see.
Sunny: we are able to get the data from the… we are able to get data from where? From the CSV file also. So, how many rows we have? We have 3 rows. So, related to each and every row, you will find out the document object. Got it?
Sunny: Related to each and every row, you will find out the document object.
Sunny: So, what, I'm doing, guys, so over here, I'm just going to be keep it inside where inside the variable, and I can show you what, I can show you the document, okay? I can show you each and every document, just a second.
Sunny: So, CSV, talk.
Sunny: Now, if you wanted to check the first document, now see, just write 0, okay? So, 0 means the first document, the first row. Now, you can check out the metadata of it, so just call the metadata on top of it, see? You will get what? You will get the metadata, okay?
Sunny: So, see, this is the metadata. Now, you can check out what we have inside the metadata. I hope it is clearly visible. So, inside that, you have a path of the file, and the row is 0. Okay, row 0 means the first row.
Sunny: Now, you can check out, how many rows are there inside the CSV file. So, this is my sample CSV. Let me open the sample CSV. See, this is my sample CSV. So, inside this sample CSV, we have this policy ID, department, topic, detail, last update.
Sunny: The five column we have, okay, and related to this column, we have what? We have the values. So let me show you the values also, how you will get the values, guys. You just need to call the page content instead of the metadata. So once you will call the page content, okay, you will get the values. Now see, this is the values.
Sunny: Let me call the print statement.
Sunny: Okay, so these are the value from the first row.
Sunny: Got it, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: Even you can pass the multiple files also. That is also possible.
Sunny: Okay? You can pass the multiple files also over here. You can run the for loop, even you can pass the multiple files. That kind of function is also available inside the LangChain, which is taking an input as a multiple files.
Sunny: Got it.
Sunny: Is this part clear to all of you guys? Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: If this part is clear, just let me know in the chat so that we can proceed. See, guys, these things are very, very easy.
Sunny: So don't make it complicated. Again.
Sunny: It's a self-explanatory thing. If you are going through with this entire thing by yourself also, no? You will be able to understand. Okay? You will be able to understand. Now, why I am showing you all this loader? Because whenever we are creating a rack, guys, the data may come from anywhere.
Sunny: Data may come from where, data may come from anywhere, okay?
Sunny: in-page content for the CSV data will be key value format. You can check out over here, no? Just print this…
Sunny: Page content. Just a second.
Sunny: Output is collapsed, so I can check out another shell.
Sunny: Yeah, it is in a key and value format, so this is the key, means column name, and it's a value associated with that. Got it, Lakshmi Ghan?
Sunny: Okay. No.
Sunny: let's do one thing, guys. Let's understand some other function. So, along with the CSV loader, we have the JSON loader also. Simple one, right? So, already I imported the JSON loader. Let me…
Sunny: show you the practical around to that as well. See, JSON loader is there. I'm just, creating an object of it, of the JSON loader.
Sunny: Okay, and then I'm passing a file, file path. So I kept the JSON file also, now I can simply copy the path and I keep it over here.
Sunny: See, this is the JSON path.
Sunny: Okay, now what I'll do, guys, I'll create an object of it. So, let me create an object. JSON.
Sunny: underscore loader. Okay?
Sunny: So, see, it is asking about the JQ schema.
Sunny: Okay, so we have to mention the JQ schema. Now, let's read out what is the JQ schema. So, you can read out the detail of each and every argument over here. So, first, the file path would be there. The second is the JQ schema. The JQ schema to use the extracted data or text from the JSON, okay?
Sunny: So, let me do one thing, guys. Let me mention the JQ schema. How I can mention that? Just a second. See, this is the way, basically, where I can mention. So, I just need to…
Sunny: mention the schema, okay?
Sunny: So, just a second, guys.
Sunny: Let me mention after this particular parameter. So here is my path, here is my JQ schema. Now, if I'm going to be executed.
Sunny: So, see, I'm able to get the JSON loader, okay? So, this is my JSON loader, this is my object. Now, if I'll call load method on top of it, what I'll be getting, guys, I will be getting the data.
Sunny: That is saying, expected page content is string, but got a class dict instead. Okay. So, for that, guys, what I will have to do, basically I will have to mention one more parameter over here, right?
Sunny: The parameter name is going to be what? Text content.
Sunny: is equal to false, okay? So, this particular parameter will have to mention. Now, if I'm going to be executed, guys, I will be able to get my data, right? So, this is each and every JSON object which I'm able to fetch from where? From the JSON file. Now, see, inside the JSON file, how many objects we have? We have 3 objects. This is the first JSON object.
Sunny: This is the second JSON object, now this is the third JSON object, right? Now, I can show you how the data looks like.
Sunny: So here, basically, what I'm doing, I am writing… I'm keeping this data inside the variable. So this is what… this is my docs. Now, what I'm doing, I'm just checking the first document.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, here is my first document. Now, what I'll do, guys, I'll call the metadata
Sunny: Okay, so metadata. Now you will find out the metadata. See, this is the metadata. And then, the actual value is the page content. So the actual value will be there.
Sunny: It would be inside the page.
Sunny: content, okay? So see, guys, this is my JSON object, which I'm able to fetch. It is just, it is just a JSON loader, which we generally do inside the Python, okay? It is similar to that only, this JSON loader. Nothing is special.
Sunny: But yeah, we are, doing it, via LangChain. Okay, so we are using the LangChain wrapper, and then we are, able to get this JSON object. See, guys, this is what, this is my
Sunny: Okay? This one. ID is there, title is there, content is there, then metadata is there. I think in the same way, basically, you will find out this JSON object. The JSON data, which I kept inside the .json file.
Sunny: So tell me, guys, is it making sense? Is it clear to all of you? Everyone is able to understand it or not? Very easy, very easy to understand. Once you will go through with this practical, it is going to be very, very clear.
Sunny: Yes?
Sunny: Or no.
Sunny: Yeah, you can, basically create your own document object, and you can add the metadata over there. I will show you, in the upcoming session, okay? In the upcoming class, we are going to be discuss that. How to create your custom JSON object.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, what is this JSON schema? JSON schema is nothing, it is just telling you which part needs to be extracted from the JSON file. So, if you will look into the JSON file, so the data is available, this JSON object is available inside the list.
Sunny: So from this list only, we have to extract the JSON document. Okay, so what I mentioned, I mentioned dot list. So from that list only, we have to extract the JSON document. Got it guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: Tell me yes or no, is it clear? What is the meaning of this JSON schema? So this JSON object, actually, it is available in the form of list, okay? So from the list only, we are going to be extract that.
Sunny: Now, why we are mentioning this text content is equal to false? So, we are mentioning this text content is equal to false because
Sunny: This extract content is already a plain string.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: the extract content, the JSON content, basically, which we are going to be extract. Now, over here, you will find out it's a plain string. Okay, this one.
Sunny: This one. This is the plain string. Okay?
Sunny: So by default, what I'm doing, I'm keeping it false. This text content, I'm keeping it false. So automatically, basically, it will extract the data as a string only. This one, this JSON object basically is going to be extracted as a string only. Got it?
Sunny: you can keep it true also, so let's see if I'm going to keep it true, so what I'll be getting, even I can show you that also, so just a second, if I'm writing true, okay? Now see.
Sunny: It's a expected page content is string, got class dict instead, right? So here, basically, along with that, will have to be mentioned some more parameter. If I wanted my data in some other format.
Sunny: If I wanted my data in some other format, I will have to keep some more, like, parameters over there, okay? Because by default, it is expecting page content as a string, but got a class date. If I want to get as a date or anything else, right? So in that case, maybe a few more parameters is required, okay?
Sunny: You can explore this part, what all our different parameter is there inside the JSON loader, and what all parameter we need to be keep, right?
Sunny: So everything is over here, right? By default, it is true, but we are getting that as a dict, right? So maybe some more parameter will have to be configured. So I'm keeping it false right now, and then I will be able to load the data as a string only. This one. This JSON object. This one. Got it?
Sunny: Okay, so now, guys, what I'm doing, I'm just going to show you the other parser also, the different other classes, basically.
Sunny: So, the other one, basically, HTML. See, I have the HTML file also. It is my simple HTML file. So, inside the HTML, you will find out the heading, you will find out the paragraph, then there, basically, you will find out the URLs and all over here.
Sunny: So every sort of data we can extract from the HTML page also, okay? So if you have any sort of data in the form of HTML pages.
Sunny: From there, also, you can extract the data. So let me mention that path, HTML path.
Sunny: So I'm just going to be copy the path, and I'm mentioning it over here. Now, see you guys.
Sunny: I will be able to load the data, okay? So, here, what I'm doing, I'm writing HTML, part, sir.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, on top of it, I'll call the load function. So, let me call the load… Okay.
Sunny: Now, see guys, I will be able to get the data.
Sunny: Now, what I can do, guys, I can simply call the metadata on top of… sorry, I simply call the page content, okay?
Sunny: So, let me call the page content, and see, guys, this is my page content. If I'm writing this particular thing inside the print statement, you will find out the entire data over here. See, guys, this is the entire data which we are able to capture from the HTML tags.
Sunny: This is the HTML text, and from here, we are able to capture all the data. So if you are getting any sort of data in the HTML format, from there also, you can get what? You can get the data.
Sunny: So is this getting clear to all of you? Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: Yes?
Sunny: Great, guys. So, I hope this, things are very, very easy, and, basically from the LangChain only, using the LangChain only, we are going to be read.
Sunny: we are going to be read all the documents, okay? Using the langchain only. Now, can we load the docx file also? Yes, docx is also possible. So, even what I can do, I can take the docx class. Here is my docx class.
Sunny: Okay, and I can mention it over here. And then, to this docx class also, I can pass my docx. Okay? So copying the path, then passing the path over here. Now what I'm doing, guys, this is my docx loader.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: DocxLoader.
Sunny: Now what I'll do, I'll create… I'll call the load method on top of it.
Sunny: Right? Load method.
Sunny: And then, guys, see, we are able to get the doc data. So, any sort of a data you can load using what? Using the, basically this, link chain, okay? And even the markdown file also you can load. Now, see, we have the markdown, import also. So, just a second, let me show you that markdown load as well.
Sunny: So, just a second, guys, I'm showing you that.
Sunny: Okay? So from the LangChain Community Document Loader, you can import this unstructured markdown loader. So just run it, guys, and create an object of this markdown loader.
Sunny: And then pass the path over here. So if you have the data in any sort of a format, okay, in whatever format you have the data, right? See, this is the markdown format, guys, this one. So in any sort of a format you have a data, guys, you can load the data, that is completely
Sunny: Basically fine, okay?
Sunny: So, if I'm going to be right object over here, MD Loader.
Sunny: MDLoader means what? MarkdownLoader. Now, just call the load method on top of it.
Sunny: Markdown loader.
Sunny: dot… load… Okay.
Sunny: Now, see guys, you will be getting the data.
Sunny: So it is saying no module name marked down.
Sunny: So, I think we'll have to be load the markdown module first, okay? Or, what I will have to do… So, here, basically, what we have, we have unstructured markdown loader. So, let me check what a parameter we have inside the unstructured markdown loader. So, here we have a mode also. Mode is what?
Sunny: mode is a single, okay? By default, the mode is single, okay? So, I think this is fine. Noticing no module name markdown. So, let me take this module, and here what I'm doing, I'm just going to be right.
Sunny: UV… PIP install.
Sunny: Markdown. I think it is a Pythonic module, so we required this particular module. This module is getting loaded, now it is done. Now what I can do…
Sunny: I can simply run it again.
Sunny: Okay, let's check.
Sunny: So, see guys, we are able to load the data from the markdown file as well.
Sunny: Markdown file, JSON file are the important one. So guys, understand how to load the data from here.
Sunny: From the markdown file, now I can directly check out the page content, okay? So inside the page content variable, we will be getting the data. Now, if you will look into this, if you will check out with this, blank chain loader, guys, so you will, basically observe one thing over here, that, the format is a standardized one.
Sunny: So, it doesn't matter, like, which file we are going to be load, okay? But everything we are getting is a document object, and inside the page content only, we are getting all the data. Now, see, this is the page content, and inside the page content, actually, we are getting the entire data.
Sunny: So this, IPYNV file is an important one, guys, you can keep it with you. So, on whatever file I'm telling you to implement the RAG, you can simply do that using this particular loader, okay? You can utilize this particular loader.
Sunny: And guys, not only this one, even you can load the data from the web also. So I can simply show you what I can do. I can basically show you that, see, this is what, this is the web-based loader, okay? Now here I can mention my website name.
Sunny: Here, I can mention what? Here, basically, I can mention the website name, okay? So, I'll take the web-based loader, and then what I'll do, guys, I will mention my website. So, let me do one thing, guys, let me go through with the GitHub or anywhere else, let me take any website from there.
Sunny: So, let's say this is my GitHub
Sunny: If you will check out the GitHub in the README page, I mentioned one link.
Sunny: So, let me open that one. Let's see whether we are able to scrap that particular link or not. So, see, visit the mentor profile. It's my profile only.
Sunny: So, you can open this profile. Now, see, this is the link, guys. I'm going to be mentioned.
Sunny: I'm going to be mention this particular link, okay? Let's see whether we are able to fetch this particular data or not. So I'm going to be open, again, guys, I'm going to open my code.
Sunny: And let's mention this particular website over here.
Sunny: And then this is going to be what? This is going to be my web loader, okay? You can mention any sort of a page, whether it's a Wikipedia page or anything. Now, guys, on top of it, I'll call the load method. So, just a second.
Sunny: Let me call the load method. Okay, now see, guys?
Sunny: We are able to load the data from the web as well.
Sunny: See, we are able to load the data from the web also. You can check out the data, okay? Simply what you can do.
Sunny: You can call the data.metadata.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: data.metadata.
Sunny: You will see the metadata over here. Okay, we'll have to put the 0.
Sunny: Now, see, this is the metadata from where the data is coming.
Sunny: And if you wanted to see the actual data, so you will find out the actual data.
Sunny: Just a second.
Sunny: Let me write the page content. See, this is the actual data, guys.
Sunny: If I'm writing the print statement, you will be able to see the data clearly.
Sunny: See, this is the actual data.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, it is able to extract everything from the website itself.
Sunny: So, how to extract the data from any website? I hope this is clear, or not.
Sunny: Can we face the data? You can check out Nikunj, you can perform that practical, you will get, right? So in backend, Yash is also there, so if you have any sort of a doubt, you can write it down in the chat, Yash will reply, okay?
Sunny: Tell me, tell me, guys, is it, getting clear?
Sunny: We did not use Beautiful Soap. See, again, I'm saying, in the backend, actually, it is using those libraries, Beautiful Soap and other library.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: So, we no need to mention that explicitly over here. In backend, it is using that. You can provide any sort of a website, and you can load it. You can load the data. Even you can provide the multiple website also.
Sunny: Right? Now guys, let's suppose if you wanted to load the data from the…
Sunny: From where, guys? Tell me. If I wanted to load the data.
Sunny: From the, basically, databases. So, is it possible?
Sunny: To load the data from the databases.
Sunny: Yes, that is also possible.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: That also you can do.
Sunny: Even from the vector, even from the SQL databases, you can load the data. So I'll show you that in the upcoming session, I'll discuss that, how to load the data from the SQL databases, okay? So let me mention it over here.
Sunny: In the upcoming session.
Sunny: we'll discuss.
Sunny: How to load the?
Sunny: Data.
Sunny: Prompta.
Sunny: SQL databases, okay? Because for that, actually, we'll have to learn… we'll have to learn… how to create
Sunny: our own.
Sunny: Custom.
Sunny: document object, okay?
Sunny: document object. So, we'll learn that, how to create our own custom document object, and then, basically, whatever data we are going to read from the SQL databases.
Sunny: We can convert into the document object itself. So that I will show you in the upcoming class.
Sunny: Okay, can we read the data from the Google Drive also? Yes, it is possible. Now, see, guys, this is the method. We can load the data from the Google Drive.
Sunny: We can load the data from the Gmail also. Okay, now see.
Sunny: We have the Gmail kit also. Okay?
Sunny: We can load the data from the Gmail. Gmail toolkit is also there. We can load the data from the various places. For that, basically, what I have done, I have created one very good document, let me… sorry, one very good markdown format, let me show you that. So, here I'm keeping it.
Sunny: Okay. Now, file-based loader, I think I already shown you. Tags, PDF, Word, CSV, Excel, HTML, Markdown, JSON.
Sunny: YAML, PowerPoint, subtitle, notebook, okay? So from anywhere, basically, you can load the data. Now, apart from that, you can load the data from the website also. So these all are the methods, web-based loader, recursive URL loader.
Sunny: sitemap loader, async HTML loader, okay? So these, all the classes actually are dedicated to the website. Then, guys, database loader, see? SQL database loader, DuckDB loader, Snowflake loader.
Sunny: CouchDBLoader, SerenDBLoader. So, from every database, basically, you can load the data. Now, even you can load the data from the cloud storage also. So, if your data, actually, it is available in the S3, Azure Blob, Google Cloud Storage, or in any other… at any other place.
Sunny: SharePoint, Dropbox, so from there, that place also, you can load the data, right?
Sunny: Now, guys, if you wanted to load the data from any other workspace, okay, from any other collaboration tool like Notion, Confluence, Slack, Google Drive, Microsoft OneDrive, okay, GitHub Loader, Trell Loader, okay, so from anywhere, basically, you can load the data. Even you can load the YouTube videos, audio also.
Sunny: So, YouTube loader, okay, generic loader, plus audio parser, assembly loader, Tenset SRL loader. So, this is for the audio and video. So, you can try out this, all the different, different loader, okay?
Sunny: And from there, basically, you can load the data. There's all the loader being provided by the LangChain, so you no need to write a code for all the separate loader, right? Everything, basically, you can do via LangChain itself.
Sunny: Understood. Is it making sense to all of you? Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: It's very easy to understand, nothing is there. I think,
Sunny: this part is very, very clear, correct? I cannot show you each and every loader, even it is not, required, right? Even it is not required, but yeah, I've given you the detail overview.
Sunny: And where you will find out all this detail, you can simply check out the LangChain documentation. So, if you will search LangChain documentation.
Sunny: Data loader. So you will simply get all the loaders over there, okay?
Sunny: So, see, just check out the documentation itself.
Sunny: Document loader integration.
Sunny: Water loaders are there.
Sunny: You will get, okay, web pages are there, PDF is there.
Sunny: Cloud provider is there, common file type is there.
Sunny: All the different document loader is there. See, I just took a reference from here itself.
Sunny: Hundreds of loader you will get over here, right?
Sunny: So just go through with it and, understand what all different loaders we have, and then you can use that loader accordingly.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Noticing, Community Loader is the… Basically, user contributed and verified. So this is the verified loader.
Sunny: Which was verified by the Langchain itself. So, there also you have to be a little caution, right? So, which loader you are using, actually.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Fine, guys, so I hope you are able to understand what all different different loaders we have inside the LangChain.
Sunny: And according to the requirement, we can utilize those specific loader. So I'm keeping the link inside the file itself, and you can take it directly from here.
Sunny: Got it? Now, I'm giving you this entire data and all everything, so that you can, do the practice.
Sunny: So just give me a second, I am providing you that.
Sunny: git add dot, then git, commit hyphen M.
Sunny: code updated for data.
Sunny: Loader. Via.
Sunny: Lecture. Okay.
Sunny: I'll write git push… You will get that, right?
Sunny: Keep this file with you, it is an important one, because going forward, if we are going to use any of the loader, we'll be using from here itself.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: We'll be using from here itself. Even directly, also, you can Google. So, let's say if you are writing over the Google, what you are writing.
Sunny: Let's say if you're writing…
Sunny: what I can write, Gmail, Loader. Line chain.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Now, if you write gmail loader langchain, you will get that, see? You will get it inside the community, means community have written that, community have merged that code inside the, langchain, okay? You can directly utilize this class.
Sunny: Right? And then…
Sunny: Basically, you can… you will be able to load the Gmail… you will be able to have a Gmail-related integration also. Now, guys, one more thing, see? Here, you can see the Gmail loader is there, but you will be required some authentication, API keys, and all from the Google itself.
Sunny: Directly, you cannot read the Gmail or Outlook, okay? You require the permission, authentication, API token, or token. So those things are required over here to make a connectivity between the Gmail and the Outlook. Directly, you cannot do it.
Sunny: Got it? So if you're going to be using that, be cautious, and just read the guidelines of the LangChain, whether it is verified to package from the LangChain itself, or it is provided by the LangChain community, okay? Means the third party, means the contributor, basically, okay? So under the LangChain community, you will find out the
Sunny: Most of the, like, classes, some of the classes, basically, are the unverified classes. So before using that, please check. Otherwise, you can write your own logic and all.
Sunny: just to read the data from anywhere, okay? That is completely possible. But if you are going to use the LangChain, then read the package description first, the class description first, and then only use it. Got it?
Sunny: Yeah, I hope this entire thing is clear.
Sunny: So, guys, tell me, how's the session so far? Did you understand this loader and all? Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: It's very easy to understand. Once you will go through with this entire thing, you will get it. So after the break, I will give you the quick summary, and then we'll move to the next level of data parsing.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Great.
Sunny: Anurag is saying, no one is addressing my doubt. Anurag, it is, like, a bit difficult, of taking doubt while I'm teaching, right? So, even Yash is there, he might also miss some of the message. Don't worry, you can ask in a doubt session if you are missing anything.
Sunny: No, I haven't shown you the image loading so far, we'll discuss onto that.
Sunny: I already given you the code over the GitHub, you can directly take from there, right?
Sunny: So, fine guys, let's take a break, then again, we'll connect after 20 minutes. Thank you.
Sunny: Thank you, Grace. Thank you.
Sunny: Okay, guys, I think we can start with the class again.
Sunny: So, I hope everyone is there, right?
Sunny: Just give me quick confirmation so that we can start.
Sunny: Okay, so guys, so far we understood how we can utilize the LangChain loader, the different, different loader from the LangChain itself, and how we can, and basically how we can load the data. Got it?
Sunny: Now, guys, see, whenever we are working in a real time, okay, so, in the real time, actually, you will find out some, complex PDFs, some complex documents, okay?
Sunny: So, if you will see over here, see, some complex PDF and those complex documents are there.
Sunny: I kept the example of that PDF. This is the example of the complex PDF.
Sunny: So this kind of data you might get over there, the invoices, images inside the PDF, okay, tables, along with the tables, some text and all, everything would be there, right? So how to handle this type of data?
Sunny: Now, see, I kept one Excel file also, so if you are working in real time, right? So, there, basically, you will get some Excel-related data also, okay? So, let me show you that in a file explorer. Just a second.
Sunny: So, let me open it.
Sunny: So, this is the… this is what, guys? This is the Excel file. So, inside Excel, basically, we can structure… we can structure our data. So, we have record ID, client name, document type, source file, invoice, contact number. This kind of data are the pretty common one, right?
Sunny: if you are doing any inventory management or something like that, right? So, you will find out a lot these kind of, file, okay? This, kind of Excel file. So, now, in every, CRM tool, basically, you will get this kind of CR… this kind of Excel file, okay?
Sunny: So, at whatever level you are going to be, at whatever level, basically, you are going to be managing the data, okay, in any ERP tool, in any CRM tool.
Sunny: Right? I think many of you basically are from the SES background. SES is what provides the ERP system for managing the data and all, correct?
Sunny: So whether it's HR data, whether it's, finance data, or it's, CRM data, or any other kind of data, right? So there, basically, we will find out a lot, these kind of data, okay? The Excel data and all.
Sunny: So, yeah, on top of these data as well, we can build up the RAG system, right? So, even I can show you an example. If you have a… if you have what? If you have the, this one, the Excel file or the table, kind of data, right? Tabular data.
Sunny: Then on top of that, how you can build up the, RAG system. Okay, it's pretty easy, pretty, basically, simple, right? Not very complex. If we are using LangChain, then I think we can do it very, very easily. Got it?
Sunny: So, now, see, this kind of data is also there. Now, again, the PDF is also there. This is the PDF, guys, which I was showing you. So, how many of you, you have encountered these kind of PDF in a real time?
Sunny: or not PDF, basically, even the DOCX file also. So, even the DOCX… in the DOCX also, the flowchart, okay, the tables, the images, okay, the different, format of the table, the different structure of the table.
Sunny: Okay, now these kind of images, the invoices, the scanned images also, it might be there, right? So…
Sunny: this kind of data are the pretty common. So what I'm doing, guys, I am, going to show you, the way, basically, how you can parse this kind of PDF. Got it? How, basically, you can parse this kind of PDF.
Sunny: Now, yeah, this is correct in SOP also, right? In multiple SOPs, basically, you will find out these kind of data, right? A complex data, right?
Sunny: So, here…
Sunny: What I'm doing, guys, so, first of all, let me show you that code. Now, I'm not, writing anything now inside this notebook. Okay, so inside this notebook, let's keep all the link and loader.
Sunny: So, anytime you are required, anytime, you wanted to refresh your LangChain, loader-related, knowledge, right? So, you can go through with this particular file, and you can do it, right? So, here it is.
Sunny: This one. And even though it… even if it is required anywhere, right? So just take out that code from here and utilize that. Got it? So it is just for your… It is for what, guys? It is just for your, revision purpose, okay?
Sunny: Now, the next thing is what? So, inside this data parsing tool, so I am going to write some advanced parser. Okay, so let me do one thing, let me select the kernel, and here I am going to write a print statement, that all okay.
Sunny: and see all okay. Now, what I am doing, guys, so I am giving you one code, Okay.
Sunny: So, just a second…
Sunny: And using that particular code, guys, we are going to be extract each and every sort of information, right? So, see, this is a code, basically. Now, guys, just look into this code, and just tell me, so what we are using inside this code for extracting our data?
Sunny: What we are using from inside this code for extracting our data.
Sunny: So, if you will look into this code, okay, so where it went… Just a second.
Sunny: Yeah, so if you will look into this particular code, guys, so here you will find out that we are going to write everything from scratch over here.
Sunny: Got it? We are going to be write everything from scratch over here. We are not going to use any sort of a framework for extracting a data, okay? The framework, like, what? The framework, like, DocLink, the framework, like, LlamaParser, Structure.io, Unstructure.io, Parser.io.
Sunny: a different other kind of framework. We are not going to be use those framework as of now, okay? So what we are doing, guys, so here we are going to be write a complete code from scratch, okay? Using the PDF Plumber, PyMU PDF, right? Using those particular packages. Now.
Sunny: From wherever we are going to be collect our data, guys, right? From wherever we are going to be collect our data, okay, the data, basically, we can convert into the LangChain document. Because going forward, for building our RAG pipeline, or for our Agentic RAG pipeline, or for our Agentic system.
Sunny: we are going to use what? We are going to be using the LangChain and the LangGraph, right? So, if we are using that framework, right, so, we'll have to keep all the things as standardized, according to the LangChain itself.
Sunny: So, if you are extracting your data from anywhere, from any sort of a page, from any sort of a document, right, will have to be converted into the document format, okay? This document class format. It is nothing, guys, it is just, basically a data class, okay?
Sunny: even you can create your own data class like this, it is very simple. So, LangChain is providing us one data class, or document class, okay? We can directly initialize this document class with our own custom data.
Sunny: So, right now, maybe you are not able to get this part, but tomorrow… sorry, in the next class, guys, when I will explain the vector database.
Sunny: Along with the vector database, I'll discuss about the chunking and the embedding also, okay? So there, I will create some custom document from my own data, from some Excel data, okay? And so you will understand that. So in the next class, guys, we are going to be start with a vector database. But before that, I will give you the couple of example of the dockling of the llama parser, okay? So you could be familiar with those or data parsing library as well.
Sunny: But if you wanted to deep dive into the each and every level of this parsing library, then I've shown you the data places.
Sunny: the different, different data links and all, and those libraries, right? So, you can do some practical from your end. Or if you want, I can give you one good assignment also, so you can solve that assignment. I think that will give you the very good clarity. Got it?
Sunny: So, here, now guys, see.
Sunny: So, here, guys, you can see we have, all this, different, different library. Os, JSON, I think you're already familiar. FITS is a library for reading the data. So, okay, so, from the PDF. It, again, it is, using the PyMU PDF in the backend. Then PDF Plumber is there. Pandas for arranging the data in the data frames.
Sunny: PIL for interacting with the images. Pathlib, just to, like, get the standardized path, okay, in the Windows or in Linux, right? Accordingly, it will convert my path into the, OS-specific path.
Sunny: Then this is to convert my custom data into the document, right? So we have these many libraries. Now, after that, guys, what I'm doing… so here, basically, I have some file path.
Sunny: So, let me mention some file path over here. You can see the file path. Now, what I'm doing, guys, so let me check out the file path. So, let me do the word wrap. So, first, I have to keep the PDF path. Okay, so this is my PDF path, and I'll copy the path from here.
Sunny: And then I will assign to this particular variable, okay? So this is what, guys, this is my path. Now, output directory, where actually I'm going to be keep my output, okay?
Sunny: So inside this particular directory only, I'll be keeping my output. So let me change this also. Now see, inside this particular directory, this parse complex PDF output directory, I'll be getting my… all the output, okay? Parsing output.
Sunny: Then we have our image directory, okay? So inside this, I'll be keeping the images, and I'm going to be capture each and every page also as an image, okay? So that also I'll be keeping. Now I'm going to be create my all the directory, okay? So let me execute this as well.
Sunny: So, all the directory will be created, see? Inside that, I will be getting the extracted images and the page images, okay? Each and every page, also, I am keeping as an image, right? I hope this thing is clear.
Sunny: Now, guys, so what I'll do, so over here, I'm going to be use the, OCR, okay? Now, which OCR I'm going to be use over here? Now, you can see we are using this PyTesseract OCR, okay? So, it is a very famous OCR in Py
Sunny: We can utilize this particular OCR right now for extracting the data from the images itself.
Sunny: Okay, so I just initialize it over here. I will be passing the image to this particular OCR, and I'll be able to get the data from there, right? So let me initialize this as well. Now, after that, guys, what I will do, so extract text and images, okay? So, using this particular function, we are going to be extracting the text and images from where? From the PDF itself.
Sunny: Now, this time, guys, you will see, so we are not going to be, we are not going to be what?
Sunny: We are not, going to be, basically, use any sort of a library, okay, DocLink or any other library.
Sunny: We are directly doing it using what? Using the PyMu PDF only, right? So we are opening the PDF, we are keeping the page record and the image record over here. We are iterating on top of the document. Okay, we are going to be capture the page, right? Page number, then text from there. Now this is my complete page information. Then we are going to be appended inside the page record.
Sunny: Then, guys, we are going to be iterate over the images, we are going to be find out the images. Okay, we are saving the images over here inside this directory, right? Then we are passing the image part to the OCR, and we are going to be extract the data from the images itself. So this is the complete record of that. Got it?
Sunny: Now, guys, over here, see, this kind of thing we can do using the Azure Document Intelligence with the Google Document AI, right? With the AWS Test Direct also. So those are the cloud-specific packages, right? And those are the paid ones, right? Those are what… those are the paid ones.
Sunny: If you are using the Azure Document Intelligence or any cloud-specific packages, right, in that case, you will have to pay for that, right? And that payment, that, like, the…
Sunny: cost is also not very less. You will get a higher cost if you're using recurring, right? So better use the open source one. It will, give you the similar kind of result also, right?
Sunny: And even in behind those intelligence, intelligent library also somewhere they are using this particular technology only, right? This particular technology like PDF plumber, pymu PDF and the other kind of open source package. Okay, so if you are working in the industry, so you can use this packages also and even you can use the ADI Azure Document Intelligence, AWS Tesseract, okay, Google Document AI, the different other kind of
Sunny: cloud-specific packages, right? It is a very subjective thing, that which package you are going to be used. Let's say something you are not able to extract with some packages, then you can raise a complaint, okay, you can discuss with your tech lead.
Sunny: that with this particular package, I'm not able to get this data, okay, so provide me some good packages, good, good, basically, library, right? Provide me some other type of document. So, even I can share one, story, so when I was working in one of the projects in my previous company, right?
Sunny: So, there I was parsing the PDF.
Sunny: So, when I was parsing the PDF, so at that time, actually, I was not getting a correct result, okay? Me, so many things I was not able to scrap properly from the PDF, okay? It was giving me so many OCR-related challenges.
Sunny: and the data was also a little messy, okay? If I was extracting something, then I was not able to get something, okay? So these kind of challenges, basically, I was facing. So I raised a complaint, basically to the business. I told them that I'm not able to get the proper data from the PDF,
Sunny: And it is affecting to the final outcome. So, I did the multiple round of discussion, and then, instead of the PDF, basically, I asked for the docx file. So, over the docx, basically, we didn't require that much of parsing, using the Azure Document Intelligence, or using some other library, okay?
Sunny: Because what DOCX is doing, DOCX actually, it is maintaining one XML file in the backend, okay? So directly using that XML parsing, we can parse the data from the DOCX. And when I run the parsing on top of the DOCX, with some native library like Python DOCX and the XML parsing and all.
Sunny: I was able to retrieve all the data very, very properly, okay? So sometime, basically, you will have to take that kind of approaches also. Let's say your parsing is not working very good on the top of the PDF, okay? So in that case, basically, you are going… you can ask some different type of document as well.
Sunny: some different type of extension of the document, right? Like docx and all. And on top of that, the parsing will be working very good. And in that case, also, you don't even require this Azure Document Intelligence, or any kind of other kind of parser, right? Easily, you can parse the data with the basic library only. Getting my point, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: I hope this thing is also clear. So this is a function, guys. Again, I will come. First of all, let me show you the result. So this is one of the functions. Let me execute it.
Sunny: Okay, now after that, guys, what we'll be doing, so let me extract the table also. So this is a method for extracting the table, okay? So let me keep this particular function inside the cell.
Sunny: Let me show you that what it is doing. So it is taking a PDF, it is, like, passing it to the PDF plumber library, it is iterating over the pages, it's extracting a table out of that, okay?
Sunny: Now, after extracting the table, guys, it is cleaning the table data, OK? And after cleaning the table data, it is storing that particular data. That's it, guys. So how we are going to be store the data? We are going to be store the data in the two format, first in the markdown format, and even we are keeping the data into the CSV format, OK? And even I will be keeping the JSON out of that particular data. So we are structuring that data, right?
Sunny: Now, here guys, let me execute it, so I will be getting that. Now, finally, what I'm doing, I'm going to be converting my data into the LangChain-specific format, okay
Sunny: whatever data, basically, I extracted, so I'll be capturing into the LangChain-specific format, so see
Sunny: This is the code for that. Again, I will come to this code. As of now, I'm just executing it, and I'm giving you the high-level overview. So first, I will show you the result out of the PDF, and then only I will again come to the explanation of this particular code, okay?
Sunny: Now, guys, here you can see the another, line of code, basically, we have for the image OCR document. So, using, this particular code, basically, what we can do, we can perform the OCR on top of the images. So, if I'm going to be executed, guys, this particular code, you will be getting the OCR output, right? So, total length and document, 53, is created.
Sunny: Now, guys, here we are going to be parse all the output. Now, see, we are going to be, save the output in the JSON file. We are going to be, save the images. Okay, we are going to be save the table also in the JSON. Okay, then, basically, we are going to be write all the data in the markdown file also.
Sunny: And even we are going to be stored the table in the markdown format. OK, so here guys, what I can do, I can save all the details, I can save all the data, let me execute it. So see that this is done. Now I can see the preview of the parse output. So I can simply run it and something basically you will get where you will be getting over the console itself. So this is what guys, this is a real parsing which we are doing.
Sunny: Okay, this is what, guys, this is the real parsing which we are doing.
Sunny: Now, if you're going to be use any other, parsing, if you're going to be use any other parsing library, or even if you're going to be use the, LangChain, data loader, right? So, in a backend, basically, they have written this kind of code only.
Sunny: So someone have written this kind of code in a backend, and using those code only, you are going to be parsed your data. Getting my point, guys?
Sunny: So, this is the code from scratch for parsing our data. Now, let me show you the result, guys. So, once I will show you the result, you will really be surprised that we are able to get the entire data.
Sunny: So, where the result is available? The result is available inside this sparse, complex PDF output, okay? So, first of all, let me close all this thing. Let me close, basically…
Sunny: all the, files and folder. I'm going to be open the actual, I'm going to be open the actual, basically what?
Sunny: the actual PDF, okay? So this is the actual PDF. Now let me zoom out this actual PDF. This is the actual PDF, okay?
Sunny: Now guys, what I'm doing, alongside, basically, I'm going to open the result as well. So let me open the result alongside. So over here, the first thing what I'm doing, so you can see over here, this is the extracted images. Now this is the first image, okay? Now just look over here, inside this particular document, we have this image.
Sunny: Getting my point, guys? So we are able to extract this particular diagram, okay, this particular flowchart as an image, right? So directly you can utilize it, you can pass it to any model, and it will be able to read your image, right?
Sunny: you can definitely build a RAG on top of this particular data. If you look into the second image, now see, this is the second image, here is the second image, this one.
Sunny: Okay? This is the second image. Now see, this is the third image. Okay? This is from here. This is the OCR, right? Now this is the fourth image.
Sunny: This is the heat map.
Sunny: Okay, this one. Now, this is the fifth one. So, table also is being extracted, as I made. Now, this one, basically, right? This is also one of the image, okay?
Sunny: Now, again, this is the image. This is also one of the image. This is also one of the image. Now, see how clearly we are able to extract all the images from this particular PDF. Now, see, guys, this one.
Sunny: So, this is the, one of the OCR, okay, this one. Now, how clearly we are able to extract this particular data from where? From the PDF itself. Now, see, this is one more image, okay? See, this is one more image. Now, here, you can see, so we have one more image, this is a mine image, see?
Sunny: I'm even able to extract my image also. I kept my image, and we are able to extract that. So, is this part clear, how we are able to extract the images? Means…
Sunny: We have extracted the… we have extracted the images. Now, are you able to see in the form of the… are you able to see in the form of this JPG or PNG file? Is this result clear to all of you? Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: Right? So we are able to extract the images from the PDF very, very easily. Now, right after this one, I'll show you the code from where I will show you the code from the doc link, I'll show you the code from the
Sunny: I will show you the code from where, from the llama parser, okay? So, these libraries also doing the same kind of thing. Even the unstructured.io, parser.io, are the different, are different, library, okay? Now, let me show you something else. So, what I done, guys, so each and every pages also I kept as, images. So, here, guys, you can see.
Sunny: Each and every page also, I capped as an image. So, first of all, let me open it.
Sunny: So that, if I'm not able to extract the data properly, okay, this is the additional thing, see, it is not even required, but I did… I have done that, okay?
Sunny: So, just a second, let me open this over here.
Sunny: Okay, this is over here. Now, see, this is not even required, but I have done over here, each and every, basically, page I am able to capture as an image itself, okay? So, this is the image of what each and every page, right? This one.
Sunny: So basically, this data also, we can utilize it somewhere. This data also, we can utilize it somewhere. If this data also, we can utilize it somewhere if some results are not good one. Now, this is the one thing. Now, another one is basically the table. So let me show you the table also, see.
Sunny: So, if you will look into the… Just a second, guys, this is fine, now see. So, guys, if you will look into the table, so each and every table, we are able to extract in the form of markdown format.
Sunny: Okay? This is the markdown format of each and every table. I hope it is visible to all of you.
Sunny: Right, so this is what is the structure format of the table.
Sunny: Okay, now see guys, just read out this table and you will find out that this is the exact data. So we have contract, table, images, multi-tenant metadata. Okay, see, this is the one.
Sunny: This is the one. So this is what, guys, this is the… this is what, guys, this is the, basically the actual structure of the table. Now, we can provide this particular structure to the LLM, and LLM will be able to answer very, basically effectively out of this table data.
Sunny: Tell me, guys, yes or no, are you getting this part or not? Now, sir, let me show you the other table also. See, this is the another table.
Sunny: There's another table. Now see, there's another table.
Sunny: This is the another table, this one.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Now, here I can show you another table. See, this is another table.
Sunny: This one.
Sunny: Okay, this is one more table. Now let me show you some other, different, difficult type of table. Okay, so this is one more table. Now…
Sunny: Here is the image, okay?
Sunny: So, this is also fine.
Sunny: So, page… even I can do the clear-cut number of the table, right, to the table. Everything I can do, so that is not a difficult at all, okay? So, I can provide that.
Sunny: So, see, each and every table I'm able to fetch, and each and every table in which format? In the markdown format, okay? So, this particular data I can provide. Now, over here, guys, you will find out, see.
Sunny: So, data protection, how this table is being captured. Now, see, guys, this table, actually, this particular table is not being captured. Data protection, let me check out whether it is there or not.
Sunny: Okay, so this particular table is not there. Why? Because this is being captured as an image itself. This particular table is captured as an image itself, okay? But that is not a typical thing. Even though we have this kind of table, the different format of the table, we can capture that in the form of empty, okay? I have done that in real time, that's why I'm telling you, so that is not at all a difficult thing. We can do it.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: I can see over here, the text extension is there.
Sunny: Bm, whether this table is there or not, data protection…
Sunny: Just a second, let me check. I think that is not coming, maybe, because it is being captured as an image itself, okay?
Sunny: Okay, no, it is not coming, guys. So that is being captured as a image itself. Now, apart from this one, guys, see, we have created a JSON record also. So this is a JSON record of the images. Is it visible? See.
Sunny: This is a JSON record of each and every images, now just read out each and every JSON record. Now, over here, inside the JSON record, what you will find out, guys, so inside the JSON record, basically, you will find out the images, and the…
Sunny: And, basically, the text out of the image, okay? So, OCR text, basically, out of the image. So, here, guys, this is the first image.
Sunny: Okay, so this is the first image. Even we can give the appropriate name to this one. So, OCR is skipped or failed. TestRect is not installed. It is not in your path. Okay, I think the TestRect is not working. That's why I'm not able to get the image OCR text. I'll check out why it is not working. Maybe I'll have to configure it inside the system, right?
Sunny: So, see guys, this is what, this is the one more JSON format of the image, okay?
Sunny: I can keep the OCR-related stuff also inside this particular JSON. So this is the arrangement of the data. Now, page record is there. So here you can see the page record.
Sunny: So what we have instead of page record, just see. So we have the page number, text out of the page, image, okay, width, height, OCR text, OCR text is not coming. There's the image path, okay, and then you can see the another page. So page-wise also, we are able to extract the information, okay? We are able to capture, we are going to be structure the information.
Sunny: Now, I can directly feed this information via inside the vector databases, okay? Now, see, one more page we have… one more we have. See, this is the RAG-ready, right? RAG-ready MD file. So, directly, basically, we can utilize this MD file, and we can store this particular data inside the vector database.
Sunny: And finally, on top of that, we can create our rack system. Okay, so going forward, basically, I will show you that. So, in every manner, in every way, basically, we are going to be arranging our data. And this is called, guys, this is called the real parsing.
Sunny: This is what guys tell me, this is the real parsing, actually, which we are doing over here.
Sunny: Making sense? Tell me yes or no. Now, here, guys, if you will find out, so this is the JSON format of the table. This is the JSON format of the table. Now, see, table index is there, this is a raw table, okay? And in the JSON format also, we are going to be capturing the table data.
Sunny: Okay, so from the images, basically, we are not able to extract the OCR data as of now, because my OCR is not working. I will have to check, I think some issue with the configuration, basically, but yeah, I will check… I will be checking the pytest, right?
Sunny: Right? But yeah, see, I'm able to get all the, data via inside the table record.json also.
Sunny: So we are going to be capture the table in the form of MD and in the form of JSON also, right? In this particular format, the table is being captured. So in any way, basically, you can utilize this table, and we are able to structure this particular data.
Sunny: And this is what, basically, we are doing in a real time, guys. I have done this thing a lot before creating a RAG.
Sunny: And, yes, if you're working in a real-time project, even you will also have to do the same thing, right? So, I hope, guys, this parsing is making sense to all of you. Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: If this parsing is making sense, I think we are good to go. Don't worry, guys, I'll give you the quick revision of this entire code.
Sunny: And this code, basically is a very simple one, right? And even we can utilize the LLM also for reading out these images. So LLM can also directly read out those images, and it can give you the output from these particular images. Okay, we are passing this image
Sunny: this image, okay, this particular image to the LLM. LLM can read the detail out of this particular image, okay, that is perfectly fine.
Sunny: So, is this part clear?
Sunny: Tell me.
Sunny: As of now, the result is clear.
Sunny: Yeah, in the next class, I will… I will show you that. Don't worry, we'll discuss onto it.
Sunny: Now, guys, see one more thing. We're talking about the dock link, right? Have you heard about the dock link?
Sunny: So, using the dock link also, we can do the same thing.
Sunny: Using the dock link also, we can do the same thing. It is a data parsing library.
Sunny: So, what I'm doing, guys, inside the same file, I'm going to keep the code for the doc link, okay?
Sunny: So, just give me a second, I have a code for the dockling. Let me keep it over here.
Sunny: See, this is the code for what? Code for the dock link.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: Now, even we can utilize this dock link via, even we can utilize the dock link via what? Via LangChain itself.
Sunny: So let me do one thing, guys, let me keep the LangChain-related code also over here.
Sunny: Just a second.
Sunny: So, via LangChain also, we can use the dock link, okay?
Sunny: So, just a second…
Sunny: Yeah, so this is the code for the LangChain, the via LangChain
Sunny: Now guys dockling actually dockling is what dockling is a library. It is a library for what it is a library for parsing the data. Okay, even we can embed the images. Also, I think beneath in the previous classes I already shown you that we can embed the images and we can store it inside the vector database.
Sunny: So, chunking of the images is not possible, because image is a standalone entity. Got it? So, chunking of the image is not required. Either we can store that image in the BS64 format, or we can perform the embedding of those images, and we can store directly embedding inside the vector databases. Got it?
Sunny: Now, over here, you can see, so, we have the dock link code as well.
Sunny: Let me install the dock link first. So, here, if I'm going to show you the…
Sunny: Installation part, so just a second. This, chunking and all, guys, I will be discussing in the next class, right? So this is the package, the dockling package. I'm going to install inside the current library. So UV… sorry, inside the current virtual environment.
Sunny: So, UV pip install dockling.
Sunny: Right, so let me write over here the dock link only.
Sunny: UV pip install dockling.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Now let me run it.
Sunny: You can use the DocLink for any other, document also. So, it is not, it is not only for the PDF. For any other document also, you can use it. Got it? Nawal?
Sunny: So, it might take some time, because it is having a lot of things in the backend, so let it install.
Sunny: So, did you like the data parsing thing?
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Dockling is a bit slow, unstructured IO is also a bit slow, because it is using very heavy processing in the backend, that's why.
Sunny: And we have multiple options, like Ollama OCR, Mistral OCR, okay, we can use the model also as an OCR, okay, for reading the images and all.
Sunny: Right? We can use this custom code, which I have shown you, the PDF plumber and the PyMU PDF, those one. So instead of these packages, guys, you can directly utilize, the raw code, okay?
Sunny: Array RCSG, don't worry, I will give you the revision, don'
Sunny: Don't worry, Asis, right?
Sunny: I'll give you the sort of revision, then that part will be clear.
Sunny: I will come to that. First of all, let me show you some more code execution and all. Then again, I will come to that particular part.
Sunny: What is your system configuration? My system is having around 32GB of RAM.
Sunny: So it's a good system, actually.
Sunny: See.
Sunny: So, I have a GPU that is GeForce 5070Ti, it's an expensive GPU.
Sunny: Then I have the AMD, AMD, basically, right?
Sunny: So… then I have 32GB of RAM,
Sunny: Okay? It is a good one. So the, basic configuration of this rank is very high-end.
Sunny: Okay, and I have, around, 7050X… 7950X 16-core processor, and it is, like, quite fast, this one.
Sunny: It is not a laptop, it is a system.
Sunny: It is a desktop system, it is not a laptop, because you cannot do this much of heavy processing with a laptop, okay? You can do, but again, you will have to, like, buy some high-end laptop in that case.
Sunny: you will have to invest at least 3 to 4 lakh of… 4 lakh of rupees, okay? My system cost is around 2.75 lakh, so, within that budget, between 2 to 3 lakh, actually, you can build this kind of system.
Sunny: like…
Sunny: Okay, so… now, just a second, let it install.
Sunny: Yeah, I can run the model up to 3 billion parameter, right? So, I have tried it out, that.
Sunny: So, it was working fine. Sometimes it's getting stuck with the multiple processes going on.
Sunny: Okay. How much is my GRAM? My GRAM is high, and because of that, it is able to take a lot of load. So, if you will check, my GRAM is around 16 GB. Sorry, BRAM, actually. So, it is around 16th of GB. This one. See?
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So it is able to handle the good GPU processing, even though if I'm rendering anything right, it is able to take care of that part.
Sunny: Okay, so this is fine.
Sunny: Now, guys, so I… see, this package actually takes time, so if you are not able to install it inside your local system, this particular package, then what you can do, guys, you can do it over the collab itself.
Sunny: if you're not able to use this dock line inside a local system, then you can do it over the Colab itself, okay? Because that is not your machine. That is just a, like, server which you are using, and that is being provided by the Google Colab.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: It's a… yeah, it's a custom desktop, right.
Sunny: Okay, guys, so I hope, I'm able to install the dockling successfully. Now, let's, check it out. Now, let's, basically, perform the practical use of the dockling also. And even I can show you via Llama parser as well, so that is not a big deal, okay?
Sunny: So, first, what I am doing… so, where I was, just a second…
Sunny: Yeah. So here, guys, you can see JSON, path, document, and the recursive character text splitter, right? So this, particular library, again, it is for the LangChain end, and we'll discuss onto this library. In the next class, actually, you will get a more clarity about it.
Sunny: Now, guys, what I am doing… so, here, guys, I have a PDF, so let me take the PDF data.
Sunny: So I'm copying the path of the PDF. Now let me keep it over here. This one.
Sunny: Just a second. So, this is the PDF now.
Sunny: Copy the path.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: And I'm keeping it over here, this one.
Sunny: So, this is the PDF. Now, after that, what I will do… so, see all the directory and all, everything is being created, wherever, basically, I wanted to keep the, result, okay? So, this is going to be what? This is going to be my output directory, okay? So, what I can do…
Sunny: I can, basically… Take this particular path till here.
Sunny: And I can paste it over here. Got it?
Sunny: So, here, basically, my output will be stored, delivered to the dock light.
Sunny: Now, guys, let me initialize it, first of all. So, here, basically, the initialization of the directory.
Sunny: Okay, so one more directory has created. If you will go and check out with the data folder, you will get the directory, okay? So just go with the data folder, now see.
Sunny: Inside this data folder, you will get that directory. Now, where it is… So… Sample, sample, sample.
Sunny: Inside the output, inside the output, basically, in this doc link parts output folder, we are going to be captured the output, okay? See, this is the path.
Sunny: This is basically what… this is the path, okay, where we are going to be capture the docking-related result. Now, what I'm doing here… so, here, guys, you can see we are going to be initialize
Sunny: the document converter from where? From the doc link itself, okay? So let me initialize that.
Sunny: And here, what I'm doing… see, I'm going to initialize the object of it, then I'm passing the PDF path, okay? And then, basically, it will give me the document object. So, now what I'm doing, let me execute it. It will take some time, guys, because it is doing some heavy processing in the backend.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: It's doing some heavy processing in the backend. Now, guys, what we can do, we can export the result also.
Sunny: Right, so this is done. Now what I'll do… Just a second.
Sunny: So, earlier, basically, when I have executed, right? So, it was… it has taken around, 10 to 15 minutes for processing this entire PDF. Now, see, in the backend, everything is being any slice.
Sunny: Now, it has written… whoever has developed the doc lingna, they have written the entire code from scratch over there, okay? So, even I can check, once I'll go with the, basically my browser, right?
Sunny: So here I can write, doc link.
Sunny: So you will get the official page of the doc link.
Sunny: Or the official GitHub of the DocLink, it's an open source
Sunny: And this is the official documentation of the DocLink, doclink.ai.
Sunny: Okay, so this is the GitHub of the doc link. The entire code is open source. Now you can see the star and the fork. It is a very amazing library, guys. You can use it for the parsing purpose. Now just read out the definition, so just read out the readme page of this doc link.
Sunny: So it is simply by the document processing by parsing diverse format, not only the PDF, guys.
Sunny: It can understand the other format of the document. Okay, so this is all the detail of the DocLink, right? It can process each and every kind of file for each and every kind of document.
Sunny: Then guys, here is the new… what is new inside the doc link, what is coming soon, okay, how to use it.
Sunny: every sort of a detail you will get it… get out over here, right? This is the complete documentation of the dock link. See, this is the complete documentation. So you can go through with the documentation, and you can understand this library in a detail.
Sunny: Right? If your work is around to this dock link, then definitely you can go through with the documentation, and you can understand in a detail.
Sunny: Okay, so see, this is all the detail around it. Now let me check out my code, whether it is able to parse it or not. So see, it is saying the document parsing is completed. Okay, so here what I can do…
Sunny: So, rapid OCR return the empty result. Okay, I think the OCR result I'm not able to get over here as well. But yeah, again, let me keep the output. So, what I'm doing, guys, I'm going to be keep the output.
Sunny: In the output directory. So, I'm keeping it in the MD file. Okay? So, my output has saved inside the MD file. Now, let me show you that. So, this is the output, guys. So, see, we are able to get all the output. Here is the table. We are able to get the table in the MD format.
Sunny: In a markdown format, see how clearly it is able to capture the data.
Sunny: Okay? So, this is the complete text in the table, it is able to find out. Now, at the place of the image, basically, it is just writing the image, it is not giving me anything, so let me do one thing, let me run the further cell. Okay? So that, basically, I can get the other output.
Sunny: So here, just a second, let me execute this cell as well. Don't worry, guys, we'll understand this entire code. In the next class also, I'll be discussing a little more thing around the data parsing, then only I will come to the vector database, okay? So here, you can see the complete, data.
Sunny: Okay, in the form of what? In the form of JSON as well. So, in the form of JSON also, you can capture the data. It's very huge JSON. It's going to be captured each and everything, okay? In which format that text is there, right? The entire formatting of the text, along with the table and all, everything, basically, you will find out over here. Got it?
Sunny: So it is a complete detailed JSON, in which, in this particular format, you can capture. Now, I can show you the…
Sunny: Compatible document, also.
Sunny: So, this is the, LangChain compatible document class, okay? So we can convert our data into this particular format, right?
Sunny: this document I've created, and this document, basically, you will understand in the next class. Once again, I will give you the, like, a little more clarity onto it, right? And then this text splitter and all, again, we can discuss out of it, right? What is this text splitter and all, and how does it work?
Sunny: So each and everything we can discuss, right? Or in the next class, right? So the different, different text splitter is there. So before passing the data to the vector database, some of the data we are going to be split, right? Into the different, different chunks. Got it?
Sunny: So, this part, I'm going to be skip it right now, I'm commenting it out, I will be, basically discussing the next class, okay?
Sunny: So, we'll be discussing in the next class before the vector database. So, yeah, this is all about the dockling, guys. See, using the dockling also, we can capture the entire data, right? And yes, beautifully, we are able to capture inside the MD file, and directly, you can utilize this particular MD file for what? For the,
Sunny: For what, guys? For basically the…
Sunny: the rack purpose, okay? But if we will look into this MD file, so we just have the text as well as the table, okay? We don't have the other… we don't have the images, basically. So for the images, I will have to check. I think we are not getting the image over here in the…
Sunny: OCR output, maybe a little more configuration I will have to do around the images, okay?
Sunny: So maybe in the next class, I will be discussing onto that. Getting my point, guys?
Sunny: I hope this part is also clear, right? So yeah, this is all about the parsing, means we can load the different document from the link chain and even we can do the parsing by our own custom code and we can utilize some third party library also. So I will take one more class, at least two are on top of this parsing, little more concept are the remaining one, okay? And then only I will be moving to the chunking, embedding and the vector databases.
Sunny: So, within two to three classes, we will be able to complete our vector databases, and then, basically, we'll develop the end-to-end pipeline of the RAG, okay?
Sunny: And one more class I will be taking for the prompting and all, and then only we'll be creating the complete end-to-end, this, RAG pipeline. Got it?
Sunny: So, I hope, guys, this entire thing is clear. So just be with me, let me explain you this code one more time. Let me give you the complete, basically revision of it, okay?
Sunny: And then what I will do, then basically I will conclude this session. Got it, guys? Yes or no? So, let's take a break until I can give you this entire code and all.
Sunny: So, just a second.
Sunny: Yeah, Docklink is having the OCR capability. It can do the OCR-related thing. But I don't know why the OCR is not being captured in my system. I think we'll have to do a few more settings related to the OCR.
Sunny: We have several ways of the OCR, we'll discuss that, okay?
Sunny: Yeah, Ashutosh, this will be the confusing one until and unless we are not going to understand the complete pipeline. So just wait for, till the last part of the RAG, if you haven't learned the RAG, okay? Or else revise this concept one more time. Got it?
Sunny: Give me one more class for the data parsing, the remaining concept I can cover over there, and after that, guys, we'll move to the vector databases, okay?
Sunny: Thank you.
Sunny: Yes, all type of file formatting and all, everything you can do over there. Got it? So guys, let's take a quick break, a 2-minute water break, then again, we'll do the quick revision of the code, okay? So, putting a timer, just a second, let me put it over here.
Sunny: So, quick 2 minutes of break, then again we'll resume.
Sunny: Okay, guys, so let's, do one thing, let's again, look into, this, particular code, okay? So this is the custom code, if you will, see this,
Sunny: PDF code, right? The PDF plumber and the PyMu PDF code, completely custom code. So, inside this code, we have a multiple function. So, if you will see the first function, actually, it is related to the PyTestRect.
Sunny: So, let me do one thing, let me check out whether this is working or not, so I can, create one cell, and I can…
Sunny: test it out, okay? So, just a second.
Sunny: So, let me call this particular function.
Sunny: Now, here I will be passing the image path. So, any image path I can pass over here.
Sunny: Let's say this is the image.
Sunny: I can copy the path, and I can pass it over here, this one.
Sunny: So, run OCR is not defined. Let me execute it one more time.
Sunny: This is perfect.
Sunny: Okay, so I'm executing it, now let's see…
Sunny: OCR skipped or failed, name, image is not defined.
Sunny: Name image is not defined.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: This is the one. Now, image is there.
Sunny: This is fine.
Sunny: Let me execute it.
Sunny: Tesseract is not installed, it is not in your path. See README for more information.
Sunny: Just a second, guys. Some more information is there or not?
Sunny: Digital Data Services.
Sunny: Okay, I think… Something is wrong here.
Sunny: Just a second, guys. Okay, let me set this spy tesseract. I think some path I will have to set.
Sunny: Actually, no, you will not get this Pi Tesseract directly in the Windows.
Sunny: By Tesseract, Tesseract Virgin, Tesseract OZR…
Sunny: I think I will have to reinstall this Tesseract directly from the Google itself, so just a second, let me check it out.
Sunny: Alright.
Sunny: That's right.
Sunny: T E double S E CRT, Tesseract OCR download.
Sunny: This is the official website… just a second.
Sunny: Oh.
Sunny: Installing Tesseract.
Sunny: But also the API… Again, it is a huge library, actually.
Sunny: So, if we can perform this practical in the collab itself, no? I think that would be great.
Sunny: OCR engine, main branch of the GitHub.
Sunny: Documentation installed as a trip.
Sunny: Pre-bird packages.
Sunny: Just a second, guys.
Sunny: Actually, see, if you're installing the package now, along with that also, you will have to be installed the Tesseract, okay?
Sunny: No, it will not work with that,
Sunny: Tesseract, Tesseract, Tesseract… Third-party Windows XP installer.
Sunny: It's giving me this website, I don't know whether it is correct website or not.
Sunny: Let me check it out, that.
Sunny: Okay, it is over here as well.
Sunny: 64 bit.
Sunny: And from here also, we can install it.
Sunny: From this one.
Sunny: If I'm clicking on the download now… Okay.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: No, with the PIP, it will not work, actually.
Sunny: In that case, you will just get a package. That's it.
Sunny: Yeah, I'm checking over there, but wait, it is installing now.
Sunny: Just a second.
Sunny: Why this much of time, huh?
Sunny: Okay, so what we are doing over here, guys, the code is simple, we are just taking an image.
Sunny: Opening the image, we are passing it to the PyTesseract, and PyTesseract, basically, it will provide me the text out of the image
Sunny: That's it. Nothing else.
Sunny: But for that, the test track should be there.
Sunny: It is one type of OCR, actually. Okay?
Sunny: OCR means Optical Character Recognition.
Sunny: Now, after that, guys, one more thing will happen. See?
Sunny: Now here, we are going to be extract the text and the images. I think this part is clear, right? What we are doing inside it. It's very easy to understand. We are iterating on top of the PDF. We are reading the PDF data, and we are appending it where? Inside this page record.
Sunny: Okay, this one.
Sunny: Got it?
Sunny: Now, after that, guys, what we are doing is we render full page as an image for OCR.
Sunny: So, this particular folder, no? Inside the… Output, right?
Sunny: In the data, we have this folder. Page, images, this one.
Sunny: So, this we are able to do using this particular code, this one.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: This particular code.
Sunny: Now, here we are going to extract the embedded images.
Sunny: Embedded images is what? Embedded images are these images.
Sunny: this particular image.
Sunny: Mmm… let me show you… wait…
Sunny: this images, okay? This is called the embedded images, which is embedded to the, document, okay? This one, the PDF.
Sunny: So, this is about, the images and all. I hope this is clear. Now, let me do one thing. Let me install the OCR, if it is there, then.
Sunny: So, wait.
Sunny: Mmm.
Sunny: This is the image, this is the file.
Sunny: Yeah, the Tesseract OCR is here. Let me do the setup of it, wait. Okay?
Sunny: Okay, this is fine, now this is the official.
Sunny: Oh… Please, okay, of the… Test Raktosia, now install.
Sunny: Yes, for the OCR, we need this test, right? Actually.
Sunny: Yeah, in the collab also, you will have to be installed.
Sunny: Yeah, we'll continue next week also, Mohan, but let me show that OCR result, okay? Which was not coming, no? Let me complete. Got it?
Sunny: Give me 5 to 10 minutes, okay?
Sunny: Okay, so guys, this is completed. Now, let's see…
Sunny: whether we can use it or not. So, I'm just restarting the kernel.
Sunny: And, reloading the window, okay?
Sunny: Now, let me select the kernel again.
Sunny: Okay, so kernel is there, now let me execute it.
Sunny: This is fine, this is… Fine.
Sunny: This is also fine.
Sunny: No, this is fine.
Sunny: OCR is not installed.
Sunny: Why it is showing me this again?
Sunny: Pip install is already done, actually. I already done the PyTesseract installation.
Sunny: It is there already.
Sunny: I think it is not detecting the OCR. Maybe we'll have to check, just a second.
Sunny: Oh.
Sunny: Okay, let's do one thing, guys. I'll do it in the next class, okay?
Sunny: I'll check that why this OCR is not working. As of now, just go through with this entire code from your end.
Sunny: I will do in the next class. Okay, so one more class I'll be taking for the parsing only. Not the entire one, at least two are for the parsing, and we'll, I will solve the doubt around to this code and all.
Sunny: But I hope you are able to get it, I think, 50% that what is happening over here. The rest of the thing will complete in the next class. And even I will show you the more uses of the dockling and all. There are so many other uses of the dockling.
Sunny: So, we'll have a discussion onto that as well, okay?
Sunny: The code updated, let me commit it, and sync this to the… This is also there.
Sunny: Okay, so guys, I'm syncing the changes, you can directly take it from the GitHub only.
Sunny: Yeah, I know, Dhaval, I will do it. Actually, it is giving the code, but again, there would be some mess… messed up, okay?
Sunny: So I'm not doing it in a live class right now. What I will do, I will already prepare the entire code and all.
Sunny: Then, we'll, show you, okay, this, OCR one. Because, see, this OCR and all this particular library, it gives a lot issues in the local system. If you're using uninstructured.io, dockling, or any kind of OCR now, this gives a lot issues.
Sunny: This is not with me. Even… anyone is going to be do it, use it, na? You will get. See, I had recorded so many videos on top of the rag on my YouTube channel, okay?
Sunny: Guys, if you will look into the practical law.
Sunny: any practical in the multimodal rack, I haven't performed in my local. I, like, always performed the multimodal, like, related practical over the collab itself, because it gives so many issues in the local. There are so many compatibility. If I'm going to be using uninstructured.i on the local, na.
Sunny: it will download, like, so many other files, the YOLO and all other for the OCR, and it gives lots of issues, even the Tesseract also.
Sunny: So, image… see, in Windows, these issues are there. But if you're going to use the Linux, right, or Mac.
Sunny: this, you won't get that issue, because the download is very straightforward over there. But in Windows, actually, this OCR-related download is not very straightforward. So that's why you will always face an issue over here.
Sunny: Okay, so if you wanted to perform this practical, so I would highly recommend you, you can do it inside the collab itself.
Sunny: Where you can do, you can do in the collab itself. Okay? Generally, whenever we deploy this application, now we deploy over the Linux machine. We never deploy it over the Windows machine in the, real time also.
Sunny: Okay, the configuration we are doing over the server, right? So that is a Linux server, always. Okay?
Sunny: Great.
Sunny: If you're going to be use this Mac or Linux, this download is very straightforward over there. You just need to be run one apt-get command, and then, with that package manager, you can install the pack… you can install this library.
Sunny: But guys, inside the Windows, this OCR-related issues, this dock link challenges, or deep eval challenge, whatever library you are going to be using inside the Windows, it will give the issue, actually.
Sunny: So, from going forward, what I will do, I will prepare two solutions. I will keep solution ready over the collab as well. If something is not working in the local na, I can quickly show you over the collab.
Sunny: Okay? Because I don't have the VM, inside my system where I can show you with the Linux, so the Colab will be the best option, because that's a Linux machine, that's not a Windows machine, okay?
Sunny: Okay, fine, guys, I think we are done, basically, with today's session.
Sunny: So just go through with this entire code. Again, I will take one more session of the parsing. All the doubt related to this parsing, OK, it will be clear over there. But I hope you like this session because here basically I show you very in depth parsing using the document and using the custom code. Now it's your turn. You can go through with that code. You can understand that. Take a help of the copilots and all to understand of that code. But yeah, in the next class, couple of more concepts will do the parsing.
Sunny: And I will put more light on top of the different other library, and then only I will move to the vector databases, where I will discuss about the chunking and the, chunking concept and the embedding concept, okay? Before the vector databases.
Sunny: So, fine guys, you can drop the session. Now, I will be starting the doubt session. You can ask me any sort of a doubt. So, let's, take a 2-minute of buffer, then we'll start the doubt session. So, thank you guys, bye, take care. I already given you the code over the GitHub, okay? So, just a second, let me check out again.
Sunny: Yeah, guys, the code is updated, you can take it from here. Got it? Yeah.
Sunny: Thank you, bye, take care. See you again. Thank you.
Sunny: Okay guys, so let's start with the doubt session. If you have any doubt, you can raise your hand. Yeah, Sovik, what's your doubt?
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: One minute. Hello, am I audible?
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: Hello, am I audible?
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: Hello? Am I audible?
Sunny: Yeah, you are audible. Yeah, please go ahead.
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: Okay, okay. Okay, so, so it's a question for the, assignment.
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: So, you have mentioned in your assignment doc that it needs to be from financial, or those 6-7 categories, so I'm just thinking, like, like, if I use my own data, own data means, can, can I share my screen?
Sunny: Yeah, you can share.
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: Okay, so where is the tool?
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: So, I have created a PDF file of 9-pager. This is actually… SCColors is my own YouTube channel, and I have used Gemini to write a book over the… this channel.
Sunny: No wor.
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: channel does and all. So, this is a 9-pager, as you can see, 9-pager, document. So, can I… can I use this document, to fine-tune the model?
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: Just…
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, you can use that.
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: Yeah, because you are… you are specified some financial or those kind of thing, that is the reason I asked, just…
Sunny: I can use…
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: My order.
Sunny: You… if you belong to any of the domain category, right, you can use that specific data. Otherwise, if you wanted to use any other data, right, like you are using, or you have some personal data, you can use that also, okay?
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: Okay, another, another thing is that, like, it's a question you can, you can remove me from panel. So, another question is, like,
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: See, the point is that, right now, some hackathon is going on in my office, this week and, like, last week and this week, so even if I want to take some, sick leave and all to drive this, particular thing, I cannot do because the hackathon I am leading only.
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: So, now, the point is that I don't know how much time I will get to invest on the assignment, so that is the reason I am… I was asking if the extension can be there. However, I don't want to disturb the entire thing, but just tell me one thing that you have given some,
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: like, top 5 or top 3 will get a chance to the Agentic Rack course and all, so that course can be bought as well, right?
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, you can board that course.
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: I can buy that course, because I really… I am very interested to, like, not because of the course, but because of, like, want to learn the fine-tuning. You have given a very good session, but believe you me, I am not getting chance. Even next Saturday, Sunday, I need to work for that hawakatan, because the submission is on the 13th.
Sunny: No, no worries, you can…
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: Okay.
Sunny: See, you can focus on the priority, so if that is your priority, just focus on that, okay? Complete your assignment, submit that, no worries, okay? So, don't worry about that, got it?
Sauvik Chattopadhyay: Yeah, thank you.
Sunny: Okay, Sovik is done. Now, Bhagwan, Das, what's your doubt?
bhagwandas armani: Yeah, so, thank you for sharing. Actually, this today is very nice, okay?
Sunny: Okay.
bhagwandas armani: basically, right, when… so, we are passing the document. Again, we'll attach this one to the… one of the LLM model, or how that… like, I'm trying to bring a mind map, actually. Like, you have the parsers ready, which will convert a web… I mean, web…
bhagwandas armani: a document or a PDF into markdown file or something.
bhagwandas armani: So, do we have to convert into, again, the embeddings before we're sending it to the LLM, or how does it work at a high level?
Sunny: Yeah, yeah. See, for the review purpose and all, let's say if you're working on the project where AI as a reviewer is working, right? So directly also you can pass this data, right?
Sunny: Or else, see, if you are building any RAG system, as of now, we are talking about the RAG system, no? Correct? So, in the RAG system, what we do, we retrieve the data from the vector database, and then we pass it to the LLM.
Sunny: So this raw data, actually, whichever we are extracting, we'll be storing inside the vector database.
Sunny: Then the query will be fired to the vector database. The retrieve, we are… we will be retrieving the appropriate context from the vector database, and that will be going to the, LLM, okay?
bhagwandas armani: 8.
bhagwandas armani: I don't know
bhagwandas armani: And how does the, I mean, who will orchestrate, because we will be developing a couple of racks, right? Based on my query, you said that had to be a different policy. I will ask for a different policy for some other institute, okay, or how is that course and all. So how does, who will decide that engine, which rack to call upon?
Sunny: Not which RAG, actually, which vector database, okay, which index needs to be called. So, see, as of now, you're not getting clarity, because we haven't discussed the future concept, okay?
Sunny: So once we discuss the end-to-end pipeline, you will understand that, right? So just give 3 to 4 more classes, right? And after that, this concept also will be clear. Got it?
bhagwandas armani: Okay, gotcha. And also, I've sent you mail for your time, if you can spend some time, maybe during your week, weekday, or any other time.
Sunny: See, it is possible, it is… might not be possible because of the tight schedule and all. You…
bhagwandas armani: Okay.
Sunny: And…
bhagwandas armani: Anything.
Sunny: I have seen your mail, right? When you dropped the mail. I'll reply back to that one, and we can basically connect, okay? Don't worry.
bhagwandas armani: Anytime, anytime, because, you know, which is going through office, right? We will have to get something done, so I need some of that help in the path forward, actually.
Sunny: Oh yeah, yeah, sure, f.
bhagwandas armani: Okay, yeah. No.
Sunny: Okay, Bhagwan Das is done now. Yes, Shukla, what's your doubt?
Yash Shukla: Sir, yesterday I talked about it, and you told me to show the address. I was not able to show the address, so can I show it now?
Sunny: Yeah, you can show… show me.
Yash Shukla: Let's see.
Yash Shukla: Yes, sir, that'.
Yash Shukla: So, this was the thing,
Yash Shukla: I was trying the chat, feature of any of the models which you have listed all from the assignment.
Sunny: I think you are not sharing your screen. Please share.
Yash Shukla: What's your story, sir?
Yash Shukla: Sean said, now, is it visible?
Sunny: Yeah, it is also good.
Yash Shukla: Okay.
Yash Shukla: So, sir, regarding the assignment, only the, assignment I had, done also, but, I wanted to just, you know, give a feature to it, like, ask, I will ask question, and then it will answer the live streaming, option, something like that. So, I was just exploring the option. So, regarding that, only the yesterday's, error which was coming, it was like this.
Yash Shukla: I had ran the LLM, like, met Llama 3.2, or Qwen, if you can see this 2.1 instruct, or other also, but the error is something like this.
Yash Shukla: If you can see any… I mean, there are common errors for some of the models.
Sunny: Metalama 3.1 is not a chat model.
Sunny: Try inverter parameter model code.
Yash Shukla: Sir, if I can scroll up a bit, and I can show you regarding this.
Sunny: So, why you're using Open Router here?
Yash Shukla: No, sir, first I've tried with, this, Hugging Face. For example, I've tried with Hugging Face this one model, when 2.5, 1.5 billion parameter one.
Yash Shukla: So, the error, it was coming like this, the requested model is not supported by any of the provider you enabled. So, there was only one inference provider, it was something like Feather AI. So, I don't know how to connect with it, and it was paid also.
Yash Shukla: I'm not able to understand this thing. I'm able to do fine-tuning and deep-root, training on adapter training with the help of Qwen, but I have to pay if I have to, make it chat-enabled. So what is this thing, sir?
Sunny: Even I am not able to get what it is.
Yash Shukla: Sorry.
Sunny: Yeah, I.
Yash Shukla: I'.
Sunny: This such issue, wait, wait, let me check, wait.
Yash Shukla: And sir, regarding this only, I have to just show you one model which was able to give answer. So, in this mod, sample, you know, file, I have just asked one question, role user say hello.
Yash Shukla: So this one liquid LFM model, instruct-free, it was able to answer the chat, answer the question, so the answer came here like this.
Yash Shukla: You can see downside.
Sunny: But it's open router, sir, no.
Yash Shukla: Sir, madhab, asad hai ki quen seb triye ki hai, wagi ki seb triye ki hai, dono. Lama bhi triye ki.
Sunny: Wait, wait, wait. Te ko hugging face hala ke opened outer hala ke opened outer se male rahayat uska matlah ye thulin na hugging face se bhi male hai kar rahay.
Yash Shukla: Sir, have you seen the newspaper, Bhukkhuluk, Queen Wala.
Sunny: Wait, wait, wait, sir, wait. Let me think, sir. Please wait.
Yash Shukla: Thank you.
Sunny: Okay, okay. Actually, see, yaar pe kya problem hai, na? Dekho. Problem hai, ki hugging phase, aur hugging phase of provider API hai, na? Do not different GJ hai.
Sunny: Okay.
Yash Shukla: Joseph, right?
Sunny: Toh dekho kya hai na, hugging phase, do influence provide karta hai.
Yash Shukla: On board.
Sunny: model kya liye karta hai, jo ki available hota hai, map hota hai, right? Matlab, wo basic model kya liye, inference provide karega. Lekha nagar aap koen or koen, jaise budde model access karne kar try karega na, toh aapko access li.
Yash Shukla: Honestly.
Sunny: Actually, it's an issue. It's an issue. It's an issue. It's an issue. It's an issue. It's an issue. It's an issue. It's an issue. It's an issue. It's an issue. It's an issue.
Sunny: Toh hugging face ke jo API yana wa har model ko access karne kaya wo nahi ditiye provision
Sunny: Okay, sir. Isli aapko yi wala era rah.
Yash Shukla: Chat feature, chatting feature,
Sunny: Some model kya available nahi hai? Toh aisa kaam kya kya hai.
Yash Shukla: So, that being said, playground.
Sunny: Playground, huh? Hugging Face Pl.
Yash Shukla: Yes, sir.
Yash Shukla: Are you gonna spread it around?
Sunny: In Playground, there are models available for free. Wah model is cheaper. Wah app access kar sakte hai, okay?
Yash Shukla: Thank you, sir.
Sunny: Okay.
Yash Shukla: Sir, or… or, sir, ki… after… sir, the Google Google Transformer, ba, baap ni product satam kiya tanna. So, you said ki… malabs ko chota sahi wake PDF share karte ki, this is my important concept, soonga for revision. So, jab bhi aap.
Sunny: Got it, got it. Yeah, that was not really required. I will have to check that, okay?
Yash Shukla: But, sir, I've been using it for a long time, so it was good. So, if you think yourself that you're required to share, you can share, otherwise, nothing. Or, sir, if there's a class related, sir, it's a laptop that has 8GB RAM, so…
Yash Shukla: Kya kya kya cheez nein sarju mujhe kya local requirement dot text file mein upload kar mein chahi.
Sunny: No, no, see, for the big library, you can move to the Colab for installing that, for configuring that, okay? If you're getting issue in the local, that's it, okay?
Yash Shukla: Okay, sir, okay, s
Yash Shukla: So, sir, future, concepts, we'll do it in drag, as you've told in the last of the class, or, sorry, on the collab, or we will do it, we will do it locally only, because, sir.
Sunny: only will do, okay?
Yash Shukla: Okay, sir.
Sunny: Yes.
Yash Shukla: Okay.
Yash Shukla: Thank you, sir.
Sunny: Yeah, thank you. Yes, now…
Sunny: Next out is… just a second.
Sunny: Yes, Surya, what is your doubt?
Sunny: Okay, Sunil, what's it out?
sunil: Sunny, I think, I do not have it on, but I think my hand was raised, I.
Sunny: Okay, okay.
sunil: Okay, okay, yeah, I, I had one question, but I think I googled it and got the answer.
Sunny: Oh, okay.
sunil: Very early, early, early on the 1st. Okay. Sorry.
Sunny: Okay, Sundeel is not having doubt. Venkat, do you have any doubt?
Sunny: Sawati Balakrishnan.
Venkat: Just a moment.
Sunny: Guys, do you have any doubt?
SWATI DORGE: Yeah, you can.
Venkat: Everything's okay.
SWATI DORGE: So I have a very quick doubt, Sunny. In LLM, what is the quantization and for what purpose it is used?
Sunny: Quantization, basically, to reduce the precision of the data type, okay? The weight, actually. So, we have a weight, right, in the LLMs.
Sunny: Every LLM is having weights value. So that weight value, actually, it is in a higher precision, in the float.
Sunny: Okay, so we can convert into the lower precision, into the integer, to reduce the memory.
Sunny: memory in the RAM, so whenever we are loading the model, so, we'll be loading in the minimum RAM. You can check out in the previous class, I already discussed that.
SWATI DORGE: Okay, sure, sure, sure. So let us say if any of the model, it is mentioned that Q5 quantization, exactly what it means, up to five precision, five.
Sunny: Q5, where it is mentioned, the Q5?
SWATI DORGE: I don't have the reference handy, maybe I can bring it.
Sunny: No, you will get, like, that NP, normal float, okay, int, right, int8, FP16, so this is the value of the precision, if you're going… this is the value of the quantization, okay? In which data format, data type you wanted to convert.
SWATI DORGE: Okay.
Sunny: No.
SWATI DORGE: Okay, let me check the specific thing.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah.
SWATI DORGE: He saw Q5 or something and couldn't understand for what purpose it is.
Sunny: Mmhm Yeah, yeah, please check. If you have any doubt, let me know.
Sunny: Yeah, Venkat, what is your.
Venkat: Fine. Yes, I'm from can you hear me?
Sunny: Yeah, I can hear you.
Venkat: Okay, so this is regarding that fine tuning assignment.
Venkat: So, actually, I was planning for a use case, like, you know, suppose we all get, like, you know, a lot of SMS on a daily basis, right? Whether we make transactions.
Venkat: Or, like, some offers, or any food orders.
Venkat: So, lot of financial organizations, actually, there is
Venkat: you know, scrape these SMS into their systems. So my idea is to create one like, you know, fine tune model on top of these, you know, SMS dumps for suppose
Venkat: I'll push a user, you know, complete SMS dump last 2 years, 3 years, SMS dump.
Venkat: Then I'll fine tune that data. So fine tune the model by feeding this data.
Venkat: And finally, I'll be asking questions, like, you know, on my final model.
Venkat: Like, what is the user's salary he has received last month?
Venkat: Or, how many credit cards he has.
Venkat: Or else, how many FUDA does he make? How many UPA payments we make? So, something like this. So, this is what something I'm planning of.
Sunny: Mmhm.
Venkat: Is this feasible or like for fine tuning? Is this going to be a difficult? Because while I was doing research, like, you know, using charity and cloud. So they'll most of the times they suggested that Sms might contain lot of pi information like username, phone number, lot of digits.
Venkat: So, the model will learn that, and when you try to feed a new user's SMS and ask these questions, they might hallucinate.
Sunny: Yeah, see, you can, easily build a rack, actually.
Venkat: Yeah, see…
Sunny: Again.
Venkat: This is the best business use case for RAG, but using fine-tuning can be achieved up to some level, then yeah, RAG is the best use case, that I understand.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, you can achieve, basically. So, it is a strong use case for the fine-tuning, also.
Sunny: Okay.
Venkat: Okay.
Sunny: So what is the work of the model here?
Sunny: It will just, understand the raw input, and then it is going to be generate the structure output of… of the core query, right?
Venkat: Yes.
Sunny: Like, SMS type, transaction type, amount, merchant, bank, something like that, right?
Venkat: Yes, yes. Basically, you ask any question about that user based on their SMS data. So yeah, the model has to answer that.
Sunny: You can build some POCs, so you can utilize my solution of the fine-tuning. On top of that, you can build some POCs, okay?
Venkat: Okay.
Sunny: Yeah, and then check what answer you are getting.
Sunny: I think, you can do it.
Venkat: Yeah, I have worked up to some level, I have already trying, but I'm getting, like, you know, little poor responses.
Venkat: Because I have kind of, you know, created synthetic data.
Sunny: Mmhm.
Venkat: Yeah, yeah, I'm getting…
Sunny: So just investigate why you're getting the poor responses, what you can improve, got it?
Venkat: Okay.
Sunny: Yeah, okay.
Venkat: Okay, okay, thanks, Annie. I'll explore further on that, yeah.
Sunny: Sure, thank you.
Venkat: Thank you.
Sunny: Yeah, Bala Krishna… Are you there?
Balakrishna: Yeah, hello.
Balakrishna: Are you able to.
Sunny: Hello? Yeah, I can hear you.
Balakrishna: Yeah, so this is regarding the RAG application, right? So suppose we have a PDF document with the images, graphs, and charts. And if you are parsing that using docling or unstructured and converting that into markdown files, right? So as of now, like we are storing in a folder, but how it will be stored in the production?
Balakrishna: applications. So it will be under file storage, or it will be a database.
Sunny: Production storage means?
Balakrishna: I mean, in the production applications. Say, if you are building a production application.
Sunny: The production application also we can store in the MD file.
Balakrishna: Yeah, so where will be those MD files? So it will be in the…
Sunny: Anywhere you can.
Balakrishna: storage.
Sunny: Yeah, anywhere you can keep. You can keep it with, in the S3, right? You can keep it, basically on SharePoint, or wherever, basically, you wanted to keep, right?
Sunny: So wherever your companies are lying, or to keep it, let's say you are using Databricks, you can keep it over there, in their, basically catalogs, right?
Sunny: So, anywhere.
Balakrishna: Okay, and these markdown files will be one for each document, or it can be like multiple MD files for a single document PDF file.
Sunny: Sir, it is a, like…
Sunny: Personal call, right? Let's say you are a designer of that system, you can decide that.
Balakrishna: Yeah, okay, because if there are multiple files, right, so…
Sunny: Let's say, no, no, if I'm saying a single file, now, will you try out that approach only, lifetime? No, it is a subjective question.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: If I will ask you, let's say, if I'm asking you this question to you, what answer you will give me? Tell me.
Balakrishna: Yeah, I was thinking, like, if it is multiple files, right, so again, we need to keep a track of all those file names, and
Sunny: Mmm.
Balakrishna: See, multiple…
Sunny: From the multiple file also, we can create a single empty file.
Sunny: Okay.
Balakrishna: Okay.
Sunny: That is not an issue.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: So… That is also possible.
Sunny: If, your lead is saying, okay, do one thing, don't create a multiple MD file, just keep everything in a single MD file, and write some separation and all over there, that is also possible.
Sunny: Good.
Balakrishna: Okay.
Sunny: Yep.
Balakrishna: And how about the file size? Because if we are parsing the huge file size, right, PDF of huge file, like 1 GB file, so will it run into memory issues, right?
Sunny: Okay.
Balakrishna: And.
Balakrishna: So, in that.
Sunny: Yeah, in that case, you should have a good compute server, okay?
Balakrishna: Okay.
Sunny: No.
Balakrishna: Okay, so can we split that PDF and… Create…
Sunny: You can spread the PDF, you can load into the memory, and you can work on the batches, okay, or else you can use some Spark kind of library to process those data, and then after loading, okay, in some other format, you can utilize it for the parsing, right?
Balakrishna: Okay.
Balakrishna: And one more question. So is it always suggested to use these open source libraries like dockling or unstructured? Or should we go for a paid one like azure document intelligence? And we have Google document a right? So.
Sunny: Move.
Balakrishna: Those are better for the production applications.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, those are good. If you have access of that, you can utilize those one.
Balakrishna: Okay.
Sunny: No.
Balakrishna: Okay. Yeah, thank you. Yeah, that's it, Norm.
Sunny: Thank you.
Sunny: Okay, next out is… Bala Krishna is done.
Sunny: Kamesh, what's your doubt?
kamlesh jain: Hello?
kamlesh jain: Am I audible, sir? Sir, I'm just…
Sunny: Mmhm.
kamlesh jain: Abhi, can I ask you a question?
Sunny: Yeah, you can learn from the RAG itself in the live classes, and then weekdays, you can go and check the previous classes also, okay?
kamlesh jain: So, sir, I've been requested to attend the last one, sir. I've been requested to attend the last one, sir. I've been asked to attend the last one.
Sunny: Haha, if you wanted to skip the fine-tuning and the other concept, you can skip that, feel free. From the RAG only, you can directly start, okay?
kamlesh jain: Okay, sir.
Sunny: Got it.
kamlesh jain: Thank you, s.
Sunny: Thank you, Kamlesh. Now, Krishna, what's your doubt?
Krish S: Hey, Sonny, can you hear me.
Sunny: Yeah, I can hear you.
Krish S: Yeah, thanks for today's session, Sunny. I think it was really informative.
Krish S: Oh.
Sunny: Okay, so.
Krish S: So I have a couple of questions here. So when you showed how that PDF was split into text, table, and image, so how do you kind of bring that whole thing together when you…
Krish S: get those into the vector database to maintain the context and, you know, not to lose these as, like, a disjointed information? Like, how do you kind of still maintain that integrity?
Sunny: Integrity-wise, see what we can do, we can do the semantic chunk and all.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: And then we can store the data inside the vector databases. We can store the page-wise information also, okay?
Sunny: And we can check from where the information is going to be split, we can put some custom logic, and we can aggregate the information like that, and we can store it inside the vector database. So there are many ways to keep the data integrity over here, okay?
Krish S: Okay. Next question is, like you mentioned, like, you know, using DocX was better way if you're not able to, you know, parse from the PDF.
Krish S: But you still need to parse from the PDF into DOCX, or, like, how do you kind of…
Krish S: make sure that information gets into DocX. You still need to go some kind of parsing, correct?
Sunny: Not parsing, actually, they're the conversion of the data.
Krish S: conversion, rather.
Sunny: So, whenever we create our data, right, so we create in both files, PDF and DOCX.
Sunny: So if you're going to be convert the data from PDF to docking, that is possible, but with our external tool, basically, if you are going to be write our own logic and the code and tool, right? So we might miss some information in the document layout, and the structure might be changed. You can try out that, right?
Sunny: But yeah, companies having those internal tools, those internal applications, with that, actually, they're going to convert the data from one document to another format.
Sunny: Alright, so if the direct, readily available data is there, alright, you can use it. If it is not there, then first you can convert into the DOCX, then you can use it, okay?
Krish S: Okay, so what is the final efficient format to load this into the VectorDB? Is it like JSON format or text or one of those things? What do you recommend?
Sunny: VVC deck, it's a different thing. Why? As of now, whatever I've shown you, just an intermediate way of collecting our data. OK, so once we'll discuss the vector DB, you will get what it.
Krish S: Okay, great. Okay, thank you.
Sunny: Yeah, thank you.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Am I aud.
Sunny: Okay, Amul, just give me a minute, okay? Wait, I'm.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Yeah, we're good.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Yeah, Amol, we can start with the doubt session again. Yeah, Vivek, Amol, please go ahead.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Yeah, yeah, so my question was, so this Doppling we used to… we already utilized some libraries before Doppling, right? For, passing the PDF, so is Doppling another… another,
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: another alternative to the PyPDF and the other ones, or is it something which needs to be applied as a sequence in the pipeline?
Sunny: Yeah, so Docklink, basically, it's a unified framework.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: It is not only for the PDF, or not only for the docx, it is for the multiple uses.
Sunny: Got it. If we're talking about the pipe ETF, yeah, if we're talking.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Does it have multi-model… okay, multi-model capabilities? I mean, that is the multiple formats.
Sunny: Yeah, multi-model capability, multi-document capability. OK, so many things it can do.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, it's a kind of superset of the earlier,
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: They are kind of, the language which we saw, the models which we saw, right? Okay.
Sunny: Correct. Correct. Correct.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: So… so it… it simply converts it into a markdown, and then that markdown is then absorbed by the LangChain PutanoRenderer.
Sunny: Yeah, in any format, you can capture the data, markdown, JSON, XML, whatever format you wanted to capture, actually.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, good. And the second question was, like, suppose there are, like, suppose you mentioned that images are not converted into, normal, means text are, means the, means the vectors for images and text are, they are not the same, right?
Sunny: -H.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: So, so suppose if, suppose if we have some, data, some, some text which is, which is stored in the form of images.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Then, can an incoming query, which is a text, be able to match that particular image, or relate to that image, which has.
Sunny: Yeah, see, it.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay.
Sunny: Image embedding, image to image embedding is possible.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: image to text, right? We can convert… we can fetch the text from the images, we can convert that text into the embedding, and we can fetch the relevant image out of that also. We can keep the image as a metadata. This is also possible.
Sunny: Okay, so every sort of a solution is possible.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: So you mean, like, suppose if we have image, then that the text, if we have text, text, text written in that image, then it will, it will always be, passed into separate text, and stored in the markdown pivot.
Sunny: Sorry, I didn't get…
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: I mean, I mean, suppose if we have, suppose if we want to pass an image, and that image has some text written in it.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: So will the, so will the parser always extract the text, will the, will it always separate the text from the image, and then, and then use it for the…
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Creation of the vectors for matching, and…
Sunny: You can take this approach also.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay. Okay. This, this, the text later on in the image will be separated from the image and it'll be converted into its corresponding vector.
Sunny: Correct.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay. And the, the final one, Maya, this, this question was, so you mentioned that the, initially you faced some issues,
Sunny: Mmhm.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: use dockets, and then, because dockets has data stored, in, as an attachment in the XML format, so we can pass the XML, as a semicircular format, more better way than PDF2. So, in case of PDFs as well, right,
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: I'll be… I'll be,
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: sub-images and the sub-text stored into some… into some kind of sub-format, or is it not at all?
Sunny: No, it is not in the PDF, actually.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, in PDF, it is not… okay, so it is not, okay.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: And, and the final question was, so this, so suppose you mentioned that we are going to connect a database also to RFP. Now, there are also concepts, like, some there, we can connect, some tool to our database API and then accept it.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: So, how does, how do these two solutions compare, like, like, converting the database.
Sunny: We'll learn that, okay? I'll show you the tool calling and all.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, okay, thanks. Okay, thanks for the introduction.
Sunny: Thank you.
Sunny: Okay, now, Vivek, do you have any doubt?
vivekkumar: Hey, hey, hi, Sunny
vivekkumar: Yes, it's dot regarding a study class. Okay, so the part of that data ingestion in the rag pipeline.
vivekkumar: Okay, so, like, there we are having documents which we are doing, like, in parsing and embedding and storing in the vector database, correct?
Sunny: Mmhm.
vivekkumar: And in the retrieval also, like, along with the query, like, we are also passing some context.
vivekkumar: Correct?
vivekkumar: So, I'm trying to understand whatever the documents initially be stored in the vector DV, and whatever the context we are passing along with the query.
Sunny: Mmh.
vivekkumar: how both are, like, going to help, like, like, whatever the data we are storing in the VectorDB, that's kind of, like, our source of truth, like, whatever the question we will ask, it will go and check, and it will give the response from there.
vivekkumar: What context will help here? Like, whether it's a go and update in the Vector TV, that context, and…
vivekkumar: And then it will give… Solution of that question, how it will work?
Sunny: So, once I'll show you that, you will get, right? So, just wait for 2 to 3 more classes, you will understand, okay?
vivekkumar: Okay.
Sunny: Okay.
vivekkumar: Okay, fine. Okay. So, other question, like, in today, like, in the loader, like,
Sunny: Mmh.
vivekkumar: Like, we can load the data from the S3, Gmail, and all.
Sunny: Okay.
vivekkumar: All those things, like, it's required some, like, accessibility, like credential, access key, secret key, all those things.
vivekkumar: So, loader class will have some parameter of that, or, like, how? Like, first we have to make a connection, then we have to access how it will work?
Sunny: Yes, yes, yes. Loader class, basically having some parameter. Even externally, also, you can do that. So I commented one code, you can check out that. It is related to the Gmail API, okay?
vivekkumar: Okay, so that parameter, we need to pass that, like, credential.
Sunny: Auth credential and all, correct.
vivekkumar: But it is not safe, no? Like, passing the credential in as a parameter.
Sunny: Why?
vivekkumar: Yes, it will be having, like, risk, like, in…
vivekkumar: That can be, like, through some… means, like, it will go through, like.
Sunny: It is a open source code, no? It is running on your server. It is not a, like,
Sunny: problematic one, okay?
vivekkumar: Okay, so that parsing you're saying, it will be local. It's nowhere.
Sunny: Oh.
vivekkumar: On internet.
Sunny: Correct, it's a local code only.
vivekkumar: Yeah, fine. Yeah, thank you.
Sunny: Bank.
Sunny: Okay, next out is, Murgan Amar Rohit. Guys, anyone is there, please go ahead.
amar nath: Yeah, Amr, this Amr here. Can you hear.
Sunny: Yeah, I can hear you.
amar nath: Okay, so this I'm doing the assignment. I have a question. Very often I mess up the environment and can you share my screen?
Sunny: Yeah, you can share.
amar nath: Okay, so join as a panelist.
amar nath: Duh.
amar nath: Okay, I'll see my screen.
Sunny: Yes, I can see. Yeah, yeah, I can see.
amar nath: So… I prepare a data here. This is basically a product catalog and everything for this. Every time
amar nath: I'd say, for example, I installed the dataset here, okay? I restarted the car.
amar nath: Still is not able to find the data set.
amar nath: And if you look at my current version, it's exactly… Python version is also 3.1.1. It is pointing to the exact version.
amar nath: So, I am doing something basics here. I even went to ChatGPT, Google it, I play around.
amar nath: something I'm doing wrong. For example, I installed dataset now. If you look at UV install, I just… right?
Sunny: -H.
amar nath: And then I restart the server.
amar nath: It's okay.
Sunny: Will we install dataset?
Sunny: Show me the liability, what you're importing. Scroll up.
amar nath: Oh, I'm sorry.
Sunny: Scroll up.
amar nath: Yeah.
Sunny: It is a data sets.
Sunny: And you are installing the data set.
amar nath: Oh, sorry. Okay. My bad. Okay. Okay.
amar nath: Okay, let's see, okay.
amar nath: And then I need to restart.
Sunny: Mmhm.
amar nath: Okay, I have one more question. So as I said, starting as a senior executive director in Chase. Okay.
amar nath: Pretty much AWS shop.
amar nath: You can email me, or I can email you. Think of a mainframe organization.
amar nath: Anything I can do from my Agentic AI or anything. I'm going through some of the Agentic AI plus also on your side, okay? So, any use cases which can have a quick win for me, especially on a chase card. Basically, it's the card services we deal with, okay?
amar nath: Mhmm. So you can bring customers Apple card also. We are legacy modern modernization of AWS sorry, legacy mainframe modernization to AWS platform. Okay. I'm using AWS Kira also. Okay? Mhmm. Mhmm. Think of AMR. This could be an ideal candidate for credit cards. Anything you think.
amar nath: Will add value.
amar nath: So, that's also… I'm looking… if you have an idea inside, give me… I'll email you, probably.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: You want a use case, right?
amar nath: Yeah.
Sunny: You can, build some, like, intelligent, transaction assistance system, something like that, right?
amar nath: Okay, let me give you a problem statement, so you can tell me how we can do this, okay?
Sunny: -H.
amar nath: So, it's 80 million customers out there. They are number one in the world, okay, for credit cards, Chase, okay? And they are doing Apple card also.
amar nath: Now, when you have a use case, multiple transactions, let's say, pretend there's Sunilas, Sunita, family of Sunilas.
amar nath: 5 people, different credit cards, right? And your family has everybody's credit card, the statements.
amar nath: And I want to…
amar nath: From a document management, I need to prepare, let's say it goes to three different databases and access it and then produce on the fly database, five different statements for you.
amar nath: Okay?
Sunny: Mmhm.
amar nath: Think of this use case.
amar nath: on the fly, with, less than, what do you call it, SLEs of less than, say, 2 millise
amar nath: Okay.
amar nath: What kind of thing you are thinking about any Agentic 8 solution on this?
amar nath: Or any ML model, you're thinking about it.
amar nath: You've got me for problem 7, right? Basically, on the f 80 million transactions.
amar nath: And think of it like, 80 million into a family of 4.
amar nath: I actually, on the fly, I'm generating these documents from a document management tool. Any other document management, think of any DQM before tools.
Sunny: Mmhm.
Sunny: Okay, so… just do one thing. Draft this problem statement, send it to me via email, okay?
amar nath: I will… I'm getting an email with the bounce back. Do me a favor, if you don't mind, chat me an email here again, because your emails are bouncing. Is it me? Am I typ.
Sunny: I think something would be.
amar nath: Oh, you are captured on LinkedIn? Okay. Let me share my screen. We are captured on LinkedIn. Oh.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, you can search my LinkedIn also, so… this is my mail ID.
Sunny: Just search Sunny Savita over the LinkedIn, you will get my idea, okay?
amar nath: Okay, okay, I got it up.
amar nath: Okay, sir, thank you.
Sunny: Yeah, thank you.
Rohit Londhe: Yes, and I'm audible.
Sunny: Yeah, Rohit, you're.
Rohit Londhe: Okay, so in the real-time industry projects, when you pass the documents.
Rohit Londhe: Do we test the expected output? Like…
Rohit Londhe: What is the input and what is the output?
Sunny: We can validate that. Okay, we have some framework with that. We can validate the retrieval answer, generated answer.
Sunny: Okay.
Rohit Londhe: Okay, but what about the large documents, like…
Sunny: Mmm.
Rohit Londhe: If we have any large documents which you're processing daily, right, which you're ingesting daily, so do we use those frameworks to test it, and then only we ingest it in the VectorDB?
Sunny: You can write some prompt which can review your data, okay? So…
Sunny: You can use AI as a reviewer. Let's say you have a data.
Sunny: You parse the document, now the document in a correct format, it is following all the information and all.
Sunny: So, at one level, you can put the check where the LLM will verify your data.
Sunny: Before ingesting it to the vector database, or before generating the final answer, or after generating the final answer also, it will be validate that, right? So that type of checks is very easy, you can implement that, you can sit with your SME or business analyst, you can prepare some rule, you can draft in a prompt, and you can pass it to the AI, that's it.
Rohit Londhe: Okay, understood.
Rohit Londhe: So, considering the performance and the accuracy part, like, accuracy in terms of the output that we get from parsing, right?
Sunny: Mmm.
Rohit Londhe: Which document loaders have been used in the industry? Like, what are the… any top 3 document loaders that are widely used in the industry, considering the performance and the accuracy of the Parsi?
Sunny: So that's what I'm saying, no? It depends on the document also. Okay? So, if we're talking about the PDF, so this, PyMuPDF, PDFLumber, right? So these, native Python libraries are being used a lot in the industry.
Sunny: Okay? This does a better job with the PDFs. You can write any low level of customization inside this library. Okay?
Rohit Londhe: Hmmm.
Sunny: Even, see, if you have docx, then the way of parsing would be different in that case.
Sunny: Okay, if you have data in the web pages in the HTML, the way of parsing would be different.
Sunny: So, I cannot say which library would be good. It depends on the data type, it depends on the doc… that file, basically, on which… from which source document you're getting a data. Okay? And, then you will have to do some back and forth using the different, different library. So, use some native open source library for just for the POC purpose and all.
Sunny: And,
Sunny: If you can use that also in your final production application, that will be fine. Otherwise, use Azure Document Intelligence or this other cloud-specific tool, that will also work, okay? So, again, you will have to test that, you will have to identify your problem statement.
Sunny: And then according to that only, you will be prepared a solution. Got it?
Rohit Londhe: Okay, understood. And regarding the storage of these embeddings in VectorDB,
Rohit Londhe: Do we have any constraints with the amount of data that we can store?
Sunny: No, not a constant, basically. See?
Sunny: system and all, like, is not a constraint right now, and if we have our money, then we can purchase anything, correct? So, it completely depends on your requirement. Let's say, if you're talking about the ChatGPT, so how many queries it is handling on a global level, you know.
Rohit Londhe: Okay.
Sunny: It is handling the billions of query, right?
Rohit Londhe: Yes.
Sunny: So, if we are taking an estimate.
Sunny: So, around 100 billion to 500 billion query per day.
Sunny: So, if we can build that kind of system, means the scaling is not an issue.
Rohit Londhe: Right, it.
Sunny: We can, we can have, if we have a money, they have a, like, the…
Sunny: don't have a cost, constraint, right? Then we can build any kind of system. Got it?
Rohit Londhe: Understood. Okay.
Rohit Londhe: Thank you very much.
Sunny: Thank you. Thanks.
Murugan MK: Hello, this is Morgan.
Sunny: Yeah, Morgan?
Murugan MK: Sunny, yesterday we just, discussed about our rack architecture, right? In that retrieval part, I have a doubt.
Sunny: Mmhm.
Murugan MK: So we have the user, they will put the query and that comes to the, you know, vector DB, right?
Murugan MK: So, once it goes there, there is a section called Prompt and Context. So, that should be before LLM and after, you know, the vector division. I see it's kind of isolated, or how it is passed to the LLM.
Sunny: Mmhm So, sir, I have not shown you anything around to that, I just discussed some theoretical point, then…
Sunny: I think this is not the right time to ask this question.
Murugan MK: Okay.
Sunny: Yo.
Sunny: Because until I'm not showing at least one practical, right, how you can make a conclusion of that is how we are passing a prompt and all that.
Murugan MK: Right.
Sunny: Okay.
Murugan MK: Which is, you know, the end-to-end architecture we discussed yesterday, right?
Sunny: Got it.
Murugan MK: Right.
Sunny: I just discuss on a paper right now, but yeah, I have to discuss via practical, I have to show you something, correct? Then only we can, make a conclusion. But if you wanted to check, right, I can show you the…
Sunny: rack quickly. The solution is with me at multiple places. Wait.
Sunny: So… Yes.
Sunny: Let me share my screen.
Murugan MK: Yes, please.
Sunny: So, see, we have a data, let's say this is my data, we are loading a data.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: We're going to convert the data into the chunks.
Sunny: This is one of the splitter.
Sunny: So we got the document data, right?
Sunny: Now, after that, we are storing inside the vector database.
Sunny: This is my retriever. I prepare my retriever over here.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Now, this is what is my prompt template.
Sunny: In the prompt template, you can see, we are giving the Additional instruction?
Sunny: Answer the question based on the following context.
Sunny: Here is my context, which I'm getting from the vector database. Now this is my user question.
Sunny: So this will frame my complete prompt.
Sunny: Okay? Now, this is my RAG pipeline. In the RAG pipeline, what will happen?
Sunny: On the runtime, the question will come.
Sunny: Now, from the retriever, the context will come.
Sunny: Everything is going inside a prompt. My LLM would be initiated, and then output parser will generate the output.
Sunny: So let's say I'm asking this particular question.
Jaiganesh: Oh.
Sunny: from this particular question, the retrieval will retrieve the context from the vector database. It will form the specific prompt, and then this is the final answer. That's it. This is the RAG, actually. See, complete RAG pipeline. Now, until I'm not showing you this, the further part, text is written, this DB vector databases.
Sunny: the prompt template and all, how basically you can conclude. So this is a futuristic question which you're asking to me, right? As of now, I have… yeah, as of now, I have explained you everything over the paper, right? Over the blackboard.
Sunny: So, at which stage we are right now? We are at this stage, this one, this stage, where we are loading the data from the different, different places, right?
Sunny: I can show you this thing in the one class itself. See, if tomorrow itself, if I'm going to be show, if I have, if I had to show, if I had show you this one, the entire process, and if I can conclude this rag, then who is stopping to me, right? But I'm going in a detail right now. So I'm explaining this data loader, different, different data loader. So in future, you won't face any such issue if you're going to build a real-time application, if you're working in the industry.
Sunny: We're getting a different scenario. So, as of now, we are just at this stage.
Sunny: Next week, we'll move into this stage, text splitter, embedding in the vector database, this one, this stage. Then next to next one, then we'll move to this stage, prompting, then we'll come to this. Then I will combine all the components, and we'll show you the complete RAG pipeline. Got it?
Murugan MK: If you don't mind, can I just go back to the architecture once?
Sunny: Yeah, this is the architecture.
Sunny: No, this one.
Murugan MK: I think your screen is not visible.
Sunny: Oh, is it? Just a second.
Sunny: Now it is visible.
Murugan MK: Yes.
Sunny: Mmhm.
Murugan MK: So, even… Can you just scroll up in the first diagram you mentioned right now? Yeah, available.
Murugan MK: Yes, so here we have LLM, right?
Sunny: Mmhm.
Murugan MK: About LLM, we have the prompts. I was thinking, you know, how this prompt is, you know, passed to this, because I thought, you know, it would have been in between the VectorDB and the LLM. So that's what my concern was, you know, my question was.
Sunny: -H
Sunny: No, no, it is a complete prompt, the context and the query, okay? Here I've shown you, you know, this prompt templ.
Murugan MK: Yeah, code base, I understand.
Sunny: This one.
Murugan MK: Yep.
Sunny: Okay.
Murugan MK: Okay, so my next question, like, you know, when we deal with LLM, right? So, for example, if I put any kind of confidential information or any kind of AI data, right? So, how that can be avoided, or is that something tool we can have to control it?
Sunny: Yeah, we can control with the guardrails library. Okay.
Sunny: Okay.
Murugan MK: Okay, so the next thing, like, you know, I have, you know, a requirement to create a kind of chatbot or agent.
Murugan MK: chatbot. So, in that, the requirement is to have, we have multiple documents, project-specific documents. It will be a PDF for, you know, documents, Excel files, all. So, few, documents, we have it in the confluence.
Murugan MK: So, the MS, it's something like internal knowledge or knowledge base of content. So, if any newcomer or any project… you see, we have multiple projects, right? If we have any KT kind of thing, we can just use the chatbot to understand that project, about that project.
Sunny: Mmhm.
Murugan MK: So that's the intention. Based on that, I was trying to check, you know, the connectors to connect the GitHub Copilot, sorry, GitHub, as well as the Confluence connectors. So I don't find anything in that, you know, Copilot side. Is it something we can achieve that in the LangChain?
Sunny: you can do, I will have to check, actually.
Sunny: GitHub Copilot will also provide the connector, right? Just check out the community page of the LangChain, there you might get this connector, okay?
Murugan MK: Okay.
Sunny: Yeah, okay.
Murugan MK: Sure. Actually, we want to use that, you know, GitHub repositories for code reviews.
Sunny: You can connect with the GitHub repository directly. GitHub gives you that permission.
Murugan MK: Okay.
Sunny: Many people have built this kind of solution, they are, going to be connect the document-related GitHub, okay, means on top of the document-related GitHub, they have created a RAG, right?
Sunny: So there are, you can see now, like, the RAG is, retrieving the current information of the document and all, right? What it is doing, you know, it is retrieving… it is retrieving the latest code base and latest information from… directly from the GitHub, code itself. So, yeah, that is possible.
Murugan MK: Okay. Since we had mentioned, you know, GitHub Copilot, sorry, Copilot, we just thought of, you know, putting an MCP server so that we can use that directly to the content.
Sunny: That would be the correct approach, sync GitHub and the Confluence via MCP.
Sunny: And then you can access that, okay?
Murugan MK: Sure. Is there something we, in our course content, we just have how to, you know, construct MCP and deploy it?
Sunny: I'll show you the MC.
Murugan MK: Yeah, sure.
Murugan MK: Thanks. Excellent. Thanks.
Sunny: Yeah, Jaganish, what's it out?
Jaiganesh: Hi. Hi, sir.
Jaiganesh: So, I'm basically from the Java background side, so I was trying to explore some of the ML projects within our organization. So, recently I got access for a…
Jaiganesh: Gitlab projects.
Jaiganesh: So, in that, I see, one of the projects is about, currency conversion prediction.
Jaiganesh: So, basically, the idea is that they are trying to predict, for next 24 to 48 hours, what will be the price. And, I was trying to understand, on the Python code, they were using various models, like time series forecaster, something like whole twinter, 6-month.
Jaiganesh: Prop it one month, prop it one day.
Jaiganesh: So, the question is, like, so…
Jaiganesh: So, how they chose those models, and is there any standard to choose the models, like, for this, problem, this is the model we have to choose? Or it comes from the experience, like, trying to understand, because I don't know the ML background.
Jaiganesh: So, just trying to learn right now, right? So, can you give me some idea about that?
Jaiganesh: In real time, how it works.
Sunny: ML project, or ROW?
Jaiganesh: Yeah, Yamal, Yam.
Sunny: Excellent.
Sunny: ML, basically, what you can do, no, see?
Sunny: There is no fixed rule, right?
Sunny: That's it, like, for the currency prediction, you should use this model, that model. But there are a couple of models.
Sunny: Which you can try out.
Sunny: So, you can use the profit model. It is from the… Meta, okay?
Sunny: There are a couple of other models, basically, hall filters and all. Again, from Google, you will find out some model, okay? In the time series problem, in the time series problem, model selection is usually based on the data pattern and the forecast horizon.
Sunny: Okay? Even you can utilize those Arima-Sarima kind of model also.
Sunny: Right? If you are trying with the machine learning, and the, specifically the machine learning, right, you can choose this XGBoost and the CADBoost kind of, algorithm.
Sunny: And on top of it, Google has released one more model that is a temporal fusion. TFT, something like that, just check out, okay?
Sunny: Getting my point, right? If you're talking about the deep learning, the deep learning also, you can solve this particular problem using the LSTM.
Sunny: LSTM was being used for solving this, time series-related problem only, right? So…
Sunny: Water model you can try out. The first, you can try out the XG Boost.
Sunny: CAD-Boost, LSTM, TFT. There's 3 to 4 models you can select… you can try out, okay? And check what kind of result you're getting, right? So, what approach you can take? Start with the baseline model, any of the models you can choose. Go with the XGBoost and the machine learning, right?
Sunny: Then you can try with the multiple model also, make the comparison.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: After that, basically, compare the, matrices, MAE, RMSE, MAP, whatever different kind of matrices are there, right? And pick the model which is best for the required horizon, horizon, right? For next 24 hour or 48 hour, something like that. Got it?
Jaiganesh: Okay.
Sunny: Yes.
Jaiganesh: So, so, any scenario or any cases, like, so this is the standard, right? So, we have to…
Jaiganesh: Identify the relevant models, and regard to…
Jaiganesh: Implement with those, and try to see the result, and…
Jaiganesh: And, so that's how it works, like…
Sunny: Correct.
Jaiganesh: Rail industry, okay.
Jaiganesh: Okay.
Sunny: Okay, fine. Yeah, okay, fine. Thank you. Thank you.
Sunny: Okay, guys, I think I solved all the doubts. Now let's connect in the next class. Until then, thank you, bye, take care. Please revise all the concepts, whatever I taught.
Sunny: In the next class, again, I will come up with a new thing, and then we'll discuss the couple of new concepts also. So, thank you, bye. Take care, guys. Have a good day now. Thank you.